[{"question":"Which of the following statements best describes the relative care a warehouse manager should take in securing A, B, and C inventory items?","choices":["A. Provide best protection for A items. ","  B. Provide best protection for B items. ","  C. Provide best protection for C items. ","  D. Provide the same level of protection to all items"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"While protecting all items is obviously important, the most cost-effective approach may be to spend relatively more resources on A items than on the less valuable, but larger, percentage of inventory. "},{"question":"Which one of the following would appear in the route file?","choices":["A. Assembly instructions for a finished product  ","  B. Mechanical drawings of a finished product ","  C. Work center ID ","  D. List of component items for one end item"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The route file identifies the work center where a particular process will take place.  "},{"question":"Considering the types of cargo typically carried over long distances by inland water carrier and the rates per ton-mile, which of the following modes of transportation is the barge's closest competitor?","choices":["A. Trucking ","  B. Rail ","  C. Pipeline ","  D. Piggyback "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Railroad and barges both specialize in carrying very heavy, dense, low-value cargo over long distances. A rail line laid along a waterway would make a potent rival for the water carrier.  "},{"question":"Which of the following production strategies is sometimes called mass customization?","choices":["A. Lean production ","  B. Assemble-to-order ","  C. Make-to-stock ","  D. Make-to-order"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The assemble-to-order strategy incorporates some of the benefits of mass production and some of the benefits of true customization by mass-producing components that can be assembled into one of several different versions of a product after receipt of an order.  "},{"question":"When deciding whether to acquire a component from a domestic or foreign source, which of the following comparisons provides the most accurate assessment of their relative value?","choices":["A. Simple price comparison ","  B. Relative price plus transportation ","  C. Relative price adjusted for currency exchange and import duties ","  D. Landed cost of each"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Landed cost includes every expense involved in acquiring a component (or any item of value) and bringing it to your dock, including price, transportation, fees and commissions, import duties, etc. "},{"question":"How often, under normal circumstances, does a pre-S\u0026OP meeting take place?","choices":["A. Weekly ","  B. Monthly ","  C. Quarterly ","  D. Annually"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Sales and operations planning (S\u0026OP) is a monthly process.  "},{"question":"Which of the following types of warehouse ownership might a firm choose to minimize storage costs when adding distribution capacity for a new product with a highly seasonal demand pattern?","choices":["A. Public warehousing ","  B. New construction private warehousing ","  C. Contract warehousing ","  D. Remodeled and expanded private warehousing "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"All other factors being equal, public warehousing is a good choice to accommodate short-term spikes in demand. The other choices require longer-term commitments of resources. (In actual practice, \"other factors\" may be unlikely to remain equal, and all choices have to be made with an eye to unplanned consequences for the system as a whole.)  "},{"question":"If you know the available time at a work center and want to calculate its rated capacity, you also need to know which of the following?","choices":["A. Utilization and number of workers/machines ","  B. Efficiency and utilization ","  C. Efficiency and manufacturing lead time ","  D. Efficiency and number of workers/machines "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"To calculate rated capacity, you multiply the number of available hours by the efficiency and utilization. Essentially, that tells you how much of the available time is being used and how efficiently it's being used. "},{"question":"A demand forecast determined by a panel of all the salespeople in an organization may reach an exaggerated, false conclusion by relying on which of the following?","choices":["A. Personal experience ","  B. Bandwagon effect ","  C. Intuition ","  D. Collective view of their markets"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The \"bandwagon effect\" (also called \"groupthink\") can distort the conclusions of a panel if a strong leader emerges with a convincing but wrong-headed view, or if all participants reinforce one another in reaching an exaggerated conclusion. An entire sales force acting in concert may, however, benefit from experience, collective knowledge of the broad market served by the organization, and even intuition.  "},{"question":"Which of the following correctly identifies the cost structure of trucking?","choices":["A. Low fixed costs, low variable costs ","  B. Low fixed costs, high variable costs ","  C. High fixed costs, high variable costs ","  D. High fixed costs, low variable costs"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The public builds and maintains the infrastructure used by trucks, so they have low fixed costs. But they have relatively high variable costs for operation and maintenance. "},{"question":"A logistics manager concerned to avoid breakage of cargo would be least inclined to choose which of the following modes of transportation (ignoring tradeoffs)?","choices":["A. Truck transport ","  B. Air transport ","  C. Rail transport ","  D. Water transport "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Rail provides a rough ride for cargo, resulting in more breakage than occurs in cargo transported by truck, water, or air.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements identifies the financial consequences to a U.S. firm under NAFTA when it transfers assembled materials from a maquiladora subcontractor back into the United States?","choices":["A. It pays a tax based on the value added in Mexico. ","  B. It pays no duty or tax. ","  C. It pays a duty but receives a duty drawback. ","  D. It pays use (sales) tax on the value of the finished goods. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Under NAFTA, U.S. firms that subcontract work to maqualidoras in Mexico pay only a tax based on the value added in Mexico, which is primarily attributable to low-wage labor. "},{"question":"Which of the following constitutes the primary reason for a supplier to agree to sell goods on consignment rather than selling to its customers for resale to the customer's customers?","choices":["A. Decreased inventory holding costs ","  B. Decreased labor costs ","  C. Decreased setup costs ","  D. Greater visibility of inventory management "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"In VMI, both partners benefit from increased visibility of the inventory management process, because they share information about retail demand on the one hand and supplier processes on the other. Setup and holding costs increase for the supplier, however, though they should decrease overall as forecasting improves. "},{"question":"Which of the following forecast methods predicts demand for one product by looking at data from a different product?","choices":["A. Personal insight ","  B. Historical analogy ","  C. Visionary method ","  D. Market research "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Historical analogy forecasts use demand data from one product to forecast demand for a different but similar product, such as a new product for which no past data exist. "},{"question":"Piggyback service refers to which of the following types of cargo transport?","choices":["A. Combined truck and train transport ","  B. Combined train and ship transport ","  C. Combined plane and truck transport ","  D. Any intermodal method of transport "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"In piggyback service either a truck trailer or a container travels part of the way over the road and part of the way on a railroad flatcar. All the other intermodal methods mentioned in the options are available, and intermodal transport is an important option for the logistics manager to consider when navigating long logistics supply chains.  "},{"question":"Which of the following approaches to product design is compatible with the requirement that German brewers use refillable bottles?","choices":["A. Design for production ","  B. Design for logistics ","  C. Over-the-wall design ","  D. Design for reverse logistics"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Design for reverse logistics looks for ways to make products that can be easily reused, returned, or recycled. (Whether the beer bottles can be reused or not has no effect upon logistics in the forward chain, only in the reverse chain that brings the product back at the end of its life cycle.) "},{"question":"Which of the following would be subject to alteration as the result of decisions made in an executive S\u0026OP meeting?","choices":["A. Product features ","  B. Product pricing ","  C. Weekly production schedules ","  D. Business plan"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The monthly S\u0026OP meeting deals with aggregate-level information about product families and output. The S\u0026OP executive committee can make changes in either the operations plan or the business plan if they get out of synch with one another. "},{"question":"The forecasting method known as the pyramid technique specifically incorporates which one of the following principles of forecasting?","choices":["A. Forecasts are always wrong. ","  B. Short-range forecasts are more reliable than long-range forecasts. ","  C. Product group forecasts are more reliable than single-product forecasts. ","  D. Quantitative data are preferable to qualitative estimates. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Product group forecasts are more reliable than single-product forecasts, so the pyramid technique begins by forecasting demand for the product family and then disaggregates the demand to generate single-product demand forecasts. This ensures alignment between forecasts for the group and the components of the group. (This is not to imply that the technique ignores other principles, only that it specifically relies upon the superior reliability of group forecasting.)  "},{"question":"Which of the following pieces of warehouse equipment provides maximum flexibility in the movement, placement, and retrieval of pallets?","choices":["A. Forklift truck ","  B. Tow tractor with trailer ","  C. Crane ","  D. Roller-type conveyer "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The forklift truck is designed specifically for moving, placing, and retrieving pallets. The other options either have less flexibility or are not especially suitable for moving small loads.  "},{"question":"Which of the following would not be an acceptable measurement of output for use in production planning?","choices":["A. Tons ","  B. Numbers ","  C. Euros ","  D. Liters "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The production plan focuses on the output of product (or services); pricing takes place elsewhere in the planning process.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is an input to the material requirements plan (MRP)?","choices":["A. Make/buy action plan ","  B. Rough-cut capacity planning ","  C. Resource requirements planning ","  D. Input/output control"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Make/buy action plans concern matters such as what to order, cancel, and expedite. With the information from this and other sources, it is possible to develop the MRP.  "},{"question":"According to the ABC system of classifying inventory, an application of the Pareto principle, the greatest share of revenue will be generated by which of the following numbers of inventory items (approximately)?","choices":["A. 80 percent ","  B. 55 percent ","  C. 30 percent ","  D. 15 percent "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The ABC system of classifying inventory asserts that the A items in your inventory will constitute only about 15 percent of the total number of items but will create 70 to 80 percent of value. This is an approximate application of the Pareto principle, or 80-20 rule, which holds that about 20 percent of possible causes account for about 80 percent of outcomes.  "},{"question":"Which of the following provides a point of reference for formulating the sales and operations plan?","choices":["A. Production forecast ","  B. Financial plan ","  C. Marketing plan ","  D. Business plan "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The sales and operations plan takes the business plan as its point of reference for developing a plan that balances supply and demand by merging input from sales and marketing on the one hand and operations on the other. "},{"question":"Pegging refers to the ability to make a connection between the required numbers of a specific component and which of the following?","choices":["A. Capacity plan ","  B. Demand forecast ","  C. Specific work center ","  D. Demand for the parent according to the MRP "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Pegging is the ability to track dependent demand for a component back to demand for the parent by referring to the material requirements plan (MRP).  "},{"question":"Which one of the following Incoterms indicates that the exporter has the most responsibility for transporting a shipment of cargo from the exporter's dock to the importer's dock?","choices":["A. DDP ","  B. FOB ","  C. CIP ","  D. EXW"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"While it's not necessary to memorize the meanings of Incoterms, the important point to recall is that they exist to clarify the responsibilities of exporter and importer in a carriage contract. Of the four groups of terms, the E group (comprising only the single term EXW) puts the most responsibility on the importer, while the D group assigns almost all responsibility to the exporter. DDP, for example, means \"Delivered Duty Paid\" (that is, paid by the exporter).  "},{"question":"If you were able to get a 20 percent discount on any of the following logistics expenses, which would you choose to receive the maximum cost savings?","choices":["A. Transportation ","  B. Materials handling ","  C. Compliance ","  D. Warehousing "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Transportation expenses make up the largest portion of the logistics budget, so taking the discount on transportation costs would give you the largest cost reduction. (Of course, you would have to consider possible tradeoffs if discounting transportation caused cost increases elsewhere in the system.) "},{"question":"For which of the following items should demand be calculated rather than forecast?","choices":["A. All Chevrolets ","  B. All Chevrolet Cobalts ","  C. All steering wheels for new Chevrolet Cobalts ","  D. All Chevrolet replacement parts"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Steering wheels are a dependent demand item; the demand for dependent items should be calculated from the forecast of demand for their parent items. Steering wheels are a component; the new cars they go into are the parents. Replacement parts are sold, manufactured, and forecast as independent items, not as dependent components. "},{"question":"Which of the following is a type of supply chain collaboration formalized by the Voluntary Interindustry Commerce Standards Association (VICS)?","choices":["A. Vendor-managed inventory ","  B. Continuous replenishment ","  C. Collective planning, forecasting, and replenishment ","  D. Quick response "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Collaborative planning, forecasting, and replenishment (CPFR®) is a formal description of best practices developed and maintained by VICS to help supply chain partners develop successful collaborations.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is the primary focus of the master production schedule?","choices":["A. Weekly production amounts for individual products ","  B. Weekly aggregate production amounts for product families ","  C. Monthly aggregate production amounts for end items ","  D. Monthly aggregate production amounts for product families "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The focus of MPS is on weekly scheduling for individual products. You could derive the other amounts from the master schedule.  "},{"question":"Which of the following transportation stakeholders is most likely to be in agreement with the government about the need for market regulation?","choices":["A. The public ","  B. Recipients ","  C. Carriers ","  D. Shippers"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"All market participants can benefit from well-crafted regulations regarding such matters as fairness and safety, but the public at large is most likely to be in synch with the government on the broad spectrum of regulations, from pricing through access to safety and environmental stewardship. (This assumes a government that is responsive to public demands.)  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a standardized, nonnegotiable form listing items being shipped directly to the titleholder?","choices":["A. Ship's manifest ","  B. Order B/L ","  C. Air waybill ","  D. Ocean bill"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The air waybill is a nonnegotiable standardized form used by all air carriers.  "},{"question":"The sales and operations plan would include which of the following?","choices":["A. Monthly production figures for individual SKUs ","  B. Weekly production figures by individual SKU ","  C. Monthly production figures by product family ","  D. Monthly production figures by individual manufacturing center "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"S\u0026OP focuses on monthly production amounts for product families. Scheduling for individual products (SKUs) comes later in the planning process.  "},{"question":"In the economic order quantity calculation, which one of the following statements most accurately identifies the effect of increasing order sizes on inventory holding and order costs?","choices":["A. Total costs drop up to a point and then rise steadily. ","  B. Setup and order costs remain constant while holding costs drop steadily. ","  C. Economies of scale lower all holding and ordering/setup costs equally and steadily. ","  D. Holding costs remain constant while setup costs rise steadily. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The larger the order, the higher the holding costs, because there is more inventory to hold. Setup costs tend to go down as orders grow larger because of economies of scale. (Larger orders can be placed less frequently than smaller orders, thus reducing the number of setups.) "},{"question":"Which one of the following is the most compelling reason for a manufacturer to own its own warehouses rather than using a contractor's warehouses?","choices":["A. To increase control over warehouse design decisions ","  B. To benefit from economies of scale in transportation ","  C. To increase flexibility to test new geographic markets ","  D. To increase flexibility of budgeting for warehousing expenses "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A firm can build or remodel its own warehouses with no needs in mind other than its own. Contractors offer flexibility and economies of scale. "},{"question":"Which of the following changes tend to occur as a result of adding warehouses to a logistics network (assuming no other changes)?","choices":["A. Inventory increases while the ratio of storage space to total warehouse square feet decreases. ","  B. Inventory decreases while the ratio of storage space to square feet increases. ","  C. Inventory increases and the ratio of storage space to total square feet increases. ","  D. Inventory decreases and the ratio of storage space to total square feet decreases"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Increasing the number of warehouses tends to cause an increase in inventory as each adds a buffer of supply stock. On the other hand, the ratio of storage space to total square feet tends to decrease as each facility contains nonstorage areas that could be consolidated in a single warehouse. "},{"question":"The marketing department's involvement with product management includes which of the following phases of the product's life cycle?","choices":["A. Development through introduction ","  B. Introduction only ","  C. Conception through maturity ","  D. All phases, from conception through withdrawal "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Marketing can play a useful role in planning, tracking, and managing demand from the beginning to the end of the life cycle.  "},{"question":"Expenses involved in the reverse logistics chain may be offset by which of the following?","choices":["A. Sale of service contracts ","  B. Rebates from landfills ","  C. More efficient use of warehouses set up for forward logistics ","  D. Freight discounts on shipments of returned items"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Revenue from the sale of service contracts can offset some of the expenses involved in the reverse logistics chain, including higher transportation fees for small, sporadic shipments; the addition of transportation lanes to reach specialized warehouses; and, of course, the costs to the company of making warranty repairs.  "},{"question":"When engaging the services of a fourth-party logistics provider, a logistics manager should be careful to minimize the effects of which of the following potential risks?","choices":["A. Less rapid adjustment to new customer technologies ","  B. Reduction in flexible deployment of resources ","  C. Reduction in control ","  D. Reduced economies of scale "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Transferring responsibility for logistics to a 4PL involves loss of control, so a manager may want to compensate with frequent reviews (at least at first). The upside of giving control of logistics to a specialist should be an increase in flexibility, greater economies of scale, and more advanced logistics technology.  "},{"question":"Which of the following strategies represents the traditional \"over the wall\" approach to product design?","choices":["A. Supplier plays no role in design. ","  B. Formal design team includes supplier. ","  C. Supplier informally makes recommendations to design engineers. ","  D. Supplier creates the design. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"In the traditional design process, the supplier plays no role in design. The design is created by design engineers and passed \"over the wall,\" figuratively, to manufacturing and other stakeholders.  "},{"question":"When a logistics manager removes a complete echelon from the distribution chain to reduce overall expenses, there may be a tradeoff for expenses in which of the following areas?","choices":["A. Increased transportation costs for extra miles of carriage ","  B. Increased taxes on property and equipment ","  C. Increased inventory handling costs ","  D. Increased inventory holding costs"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Removing an echelon from the network should reduce all the costs specified in the options except for transportation costs. Removing one level of warehousing, for example, will most likely increase the number of miles goods are carried from the points upstream from the echelon to the points downstream.  "},{"question":"In the CPFR model, which of the following corresponds to the order-to-cash cycle?","choices":["A. Demand and supply management ","  B. Logistics/distribution ","  C. Execution ","  D. Order fulfillment"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The area of CPFR that corresponds to the order-to-cash cycle is execution, which includes the collaboration tasks of order generation and order fulfillment. Order fulfillment includes the enterprise task of logistics/distribution.  "},{"question":"According to the World Trade Organization, which of the following is the right amount to use when declaring the value of imported goods?","choices":["A. Exporter's cost plus transaction expenses ","  B. Actual price to the importer ","  C. Calculated market value ","  D. Amount stated in the harmonized code for the goods in the cargo "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The price paid (or scheduled to be paid) by the importer is the right amount to use when declaring the value of an import. The WTO does permit other \"reasonable\" methods of valuation if circumstances warrant.  "},{"question":"An importer will often give which one of the following independent operators power of attorney to pay import duties on its behalf?","choices":["A. Foreign carrier ","  B. ETC ","  C. Customs house broker ","  D. Ship broker "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The customs house broker specializes in moving imported goods through customs, expediting paperwork (which now takes place electronically), and paying the import duties under a power of attorney from the importer. "},{"question":"In a multiple-echelon distribution network where each warehouse orders independently based on local demand, where in the chain do you find the most variance in order quantity?","choices":["A. Variability tends to increase toward the raw materials end of the chain. ","  B. Variability tends to increase toward the customer end of the chain. ","  C. Variability tends to remain constant along the chain. ","  D. Variability tend to be greatest in the middle of the chain, diminishing toward either end."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"In many chains, variance in order quantity tends to increase as you move upstream away from the end customer. This is the bullwhip effect. "},{"question":"Place the following modes of transportation in order of rate per ton-mile for carrying cargo, with I being the lowest rates and IV being the highest.","choices":["I. ","\tRail ","\tII. ","\tAir "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Water transport offers the lowest rates per ton, much lower even than rail, which is second. Trucking is considerably more expensive than rail but substantially less expensive than air.  "},{"question":"Which of the following may increase as a tradeoff when a logistics chain institutes risk pooling by moving inventory from several smaller warehouses to a larger central storage facility?","choices":["A. Delivery lead times ","  B. Number of stockouts ","  C. Total amount of inventory held at one time ","  D. Inventory handling costs"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Risk pooling is a means of reducing the risk of stockouts by consolidating inventory in a central warehouse. With a larger store of goods in the central warehouse, even the largest, unexpected order will have less chance of exhausting the inventory, as it might in a smaller warehouse. With fewer facilities adding safety stock to their orders (plus the lower stockout risk), the total amount of inventory can be reduced, and less inventory means lower holding and handling expenses. Lead times may go up, however, for deliveries made to customers that are more distant from the central warehouse than from the smaller facilities it replaced. "},{"question":"Which one of the following is the most significant drawback of specialized package carriers such as FedEx and DHL?","choices":["A. Too expensive for small businesses to use economically ","  B. Lack of multimodal capability ","  C. Lack of flexibility in pickup and delivery locations ","  D. Price "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"With their intermodal networks, FedEx, UPS, and DHL offer door-to-door delivery on rapid timetables, but they are not inexpensive. As delivery services, they are perhaps best used when speed is more important than price. Many express services offer logistics consultation and total logistics management (4PL) and are capable of providing small businesses the benefit of economies of scale and deep logistics expertise.  "},{"question":"Which of the following would provide a sound method for grouping products into product families for the operations plan?","choices":["A. Similarity of manufacturing processes ","  B. National market destination ","  C. Similar seasonality ","  D. Appeal to a particular age group"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Product families for purposes of the operations plan are best chosen by similar manufacturing requirements to facilitate other planning processes, such as production scheduling. (Marketing can group products in other ways for its purposes.)  "},{"question":"Referring to the table below, calculate a forecast for April using the three-month moving average method. Based on your calculation, which of the following statements correctly relates the forecast to the actual April demand of 22? ","choices":["A. Demand and forecast are the same. ","  B. Demand exceeds forecast by 1. ","  C. Demand exceeds forecast by 2. ","  D. Demand exceeds forecast by 3."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The average demand for the three months from January through March is 20 (21 + 17 + 22 = 60; 60 / 3 = 20), so the forecast for April is 20, which is two less than the actual demand. "},{"question":"When international trade is financed with a letter of credit, which of the following entities actually makes the final payment to the seller?","choices":["A. Buyer's bank ","  B. Inland export carrier ","  C. Buyer ","  D. Seller's bank "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The seller (exporter) sends a draft to its banker, who honors it based upon its assurance of reimbursement by the buyer's bank, which in its turn depends upon reimbursement by the buyer (whose money it may already hold on account).  "},{"question":"Which one of the following functional areas is responsible for demand forecasting?","choices":["A. Sales and marketing ","  B. Purchasing ","  C. IT ","  D. Executive team "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The sales and marketing area is responsible and accountable for forecasting. Someone has to be responsible for the forecast for assessment purposes, but this does not mean that other areas cannot contribute to the forecast or that the forecast cannot be shared with other functional areas and supply chain partners. Information sharing is key to supply chain management.  "},{"question":"Use of a fixed order quantity model is most likely to be effective in which of the following cases?","choices":["A. Lead time is highly variable. ","  B. Shipper is looking for quantity discounts. ","  C. Demand is highly unpredictable and light. ","  D. Production is run on lean assumptions. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Fixed quantity ordering is generally used to fill containers, qualify for quantity discounts, or both. The model works best when demand is known and stable with predictable lead times. "},{"question":"Which one of the following actions would be appropriate if the load scheduled for a work site exceeds its rated capacity?","choices":["A. Shift work to another work center with available capacity. ","  B. Lay off workers. ","  C. Reduce workers' hours to save money. ","  D. Order more safety stock. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"If a work center has more load than capacity, shifting work to another center is one possible way to restore the balance (if another center is available and has excess capacity). You can also increase available time (more workers, machines, or hours of work) or increase efficiency.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following types of third-party logistics firms schedules cargo transport but operates no carriers?","choices":["A. Consolidator ","  B. Export trading company (ETC) ","  C. Freight forwarder ","  D. Non-vessel operating common carrier (NVOCC) "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Freight forwarders function like \"travel agents for cargo,\" arranging for transport but not operating their own carriers.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following warehouse operations assumes no storage of incoming goods before reshipping?","choices":["A. Break-bulk ","  B. Assembly-to-order ","  C. Spot stocking ","  D. Mixing"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"In break-bulk operations, the incoming shipment moves straight through the warehouse to be broken down on the dock and reshipped.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following entities is responsible for issuing and updating Incoterms?","choices":["A. World Trade Organization ","  B. International Chamber of Commerce (ICC) ","  C. United Nations ","  D. U.S. Department of Commerce"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Incoterms were first issued in 1936 by the International Chamber of Commerce, which has updated them several times since then to reflect the changing conditions of international trade. "},{"question":"The S\u0026OP planning team might decide to adopt a chase production strategy because it offers which of the following benefits?","choices":["A. Protection against a sudden need to hire temp workers in production ","  B. More predictable production scheduling ","  C. Reduction of resource costs during demand periods ","  D. Reduced inventory holding costs"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The chase production strategy, also called demand matching, attempts to match production to demand in each period of the schedule. If the strategy succeeds, inventory costs can be kept to a minimum. The tradeoffs include possibilities of extra hiring (or layoffs) if demand and production don't match, plus a need to ramp up capacity to match peak demand.  "},{"question":"Which of the following parties determines the tariff classification of an import?","choices":["A. World Trade Organization inspectors ","  B. Customs ","  C. Exporter ","  D. Importer "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The exporter bears responsibility for determining the classification of the goods it sells in international transactions. It does so by reference to the harmonized tariff codes.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a standardized, nonnegotiable form listing items being shipped directly to the titleholder?","choices":["A. Air waybill ","  B. Ocean bill ","  C. Ship's manifest ","  D. Order B/L "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The air waybill is a nonnegotiable standardized form used by all air carriers.  "},{"question":"Which of the following offers the greatest security against loss of cargo when transporting petroleum?","choices":["A. Water ","  B. Pipelines ","  C. Road ","  D. Rail"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Pipelines are considered a very secure way to convey liquid cargo. Except for earthquakes or terrorist attacks, pipelines will carry appropriate freight with almost no risk of loss or damage.  "},{"question":"Which of the following identifies a risk of ordering more inventory than required to fill forecast orders?","choices":["A. Higher per-car costs for transporting the inventory ","  B. Increased obsolescence ","  C. Higher per-item costs for purchasing the inventory ","  D. Decoupling from supplier "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The risk of having inventory items become obsolete increases when amounts ordered exceed the forecast significantly. Economies of scale in transport and purchase are potential benefits of larger orders, as is decoupling from the supplier.  "},{"question":"The exporter takes the most risk in which of the following export-import financing arrangements?","choices":["A. Letter of credit ","  B. Buyer's payment from an open account ","  C. Consignment of goods ","  D. Seller's credit "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"In seller's credit financing, the seller (exporter) accepts the importer's credit card (or other promise to pay) and thus takes the most financial risk involved in any of options described.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following types of warehousing is most appropriate for agricultural supplies that might be used only once during the year?","choices":["A. Spot stocking ","  B. Stockpiling ","  C. Assortment ","  D. Postponement"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Spot stocking is used for limited product lines and highly seasonal products that can be centrally stored during most of the year and spot-stocked in season at warehouses near the places where they will be purchased and used. Manufacturers use spot stocking for agricultural products used only during one limited operation, such as harvesting.  "},{"question":"If you're planning to ship goods over the road, which of the following represents a strategy for lowering your per-pound costs for the trip?","choices":["A. Fill up the trucks. ","  B. Ship to destinations with low lane volume. ","  C. Keep the weight down in each truck. ","  D. Package the cargo to reduce load density. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A full truck qualifies for a per-pound (kilogram) discount, since the carrier benefits from being able to charge more per unit of weight. Similarly, heavier loads (subject to limits) and greater density yield economies of scale. \"Lane density\" refers to the amount of cargo traffic around the destination; greater density means more potential business for the carrier on the return trip. Low lane density can lead to a return trip with an empty vehicle, at the expense of the shipper.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following warehouse operations resembles break-bulk, except that it combines products from more than one manufacturer and may also involve product storage?","choices":["A. Stockpiling ","  B. Cross-docking ","  C. Consolidation ","  D. Assembly"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Consolidation is the process of breaking down incoming shipments from a variety of sources to mix the various products together in combinations specified by a number of recipients. (The process is also called mixing.) The mix of products may include items from storage as well as those just received. "},{"question":"Which of the following constitutes the most appropriate shipment to send by truck?","choices":["A. Heavy, low-value items traveling long distances ","  B. Small, high-value items traveling a short distance ","  C. Bulky items traveling between cities ","  D. Small, high-value items traveling a long distance "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The strong suit of trucking is accessibility, since trucks can go to virtually any commercial location. This along with size and weight limits makes trucking most appropriate for carrying high-value items of smaller size for short hauls.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following types of warehousing is most appropriate for agricultural supplies that might be used only once during the year?","choices":["A. Stockpiling ","  B. Postponement ","  C. Assortment ","  D. Spot stocking "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Spot stocking is used for limited product lines and highly seasonal products that can be centrally stored during most of the year and spot-stocked in season at warehouses near the places where they will be purchased and used. Manufacturers use spot stocking for agricultural products used only during one limited operation, such as harvesting.  "},{"question":"Demand forecasts are likely to be most accurate for which of the following items?","choices":["A. All Dodge Models ","  B. All DaimlerChrysler cars ","  C. All Dodge Stratus models ","  D. All Dodge Stratus SE models "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The forecast accuracy is likely to be greatest for all DaimlerChrysler models (and then for all Dodges, all Dodge Stratuses, and all Dodge Stratus SEs, in descending order of accuracy). The larger the aggregate, the more accurate the forecast. "},{"question":"Which of the following (assuming site- and period-specific data) would provide the number of operations that can be produced at a site during a single period of time?","choices":["A. Lead time available divided by load ","  B. Lead time available divided by total time ","  C. Total time available divided by lead time ","  D. Total time available divided by load "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Dividing the total time available during a scheduled period at the site by the lead time tells you how many operations can be produced at the site in the period.  "},{"question":"Which of the following modes of transporting petroleum involves the lowest operating costs?","choices":["A. Rail ","  B. Pipeline ","  C. Tanker truck ","  D. Ocean vessel"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Pipelines are costly in other ways, but their operating costs are relatively low (no drivers or pilots, for one thing).  "},{"question":"In the CPFR model, which of the following tasks would be performed jointly by the manufacturer (seller) and the retailer (buyer)?","choices":["A. POS (point-of-sale) forecasting ","  B. Market data analysis ","  C. Sales forecasting ","  D. All of the above would be performed jointly."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"In the model, certain tasks are performed by the buyer/retailer (POS forecasting in this case), certain tasks are performed by the seller/manufacturer (market analysis in this case), and those tasks are reconciled in a joint session. The joint session to reconcile POS forecasting and market analysis results in a shared sales forecast.  "},{"question":"Referring to the demand table below, calculate forecasts for May using both the three-month moving average (MA) and the naive forecasting methods. Which of the following statements correctly identifies the two forecasts? ","choices":["A. MA forecast = 20.33; naive forecast = 22 ","  B. MA forecast = 20.67; naive forecast = 20 ","  C. MA forecast = 21.33; naive forecast = 22 ","  D. MA forecast = 22.00; naive forecast = 17 "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The three-month moving average forecast for May is 20.33, which is the average monthly demand for the months from February through April (17 + 22 + 22 = 61 / 3 = 20.33); the naive forecast is taken from the period preceding the forecast period, which in this case is 22, the actual demand for May. Note that the naive forecast (22) is more nearly accurate in this case, because it adjusts faster than the moving average. However, it could just as easily have been less accurate if demand had changed in a different direction or by a different amount.  "},{"question":"Which of the following documents would a banker consult for information about the value of export-import cargo in connection with a letter of credit?","choices":["A. Order bill of lading ","  B. Commercial invoice ","  C. Ship's manifest ","  D. Dock receipt"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The commercial invoice is the document that states the value of commodities in a shipment. (It does not include other amounts, such as freight.)  "},{"question":"A logistics manager concerned to avoid breakage of cargo would be least inclined to choose which of the following modes of transportation (ignoring tradeoffs)?","choices":["A. Air transport ","  B. Truck transport ","  C. Water transport ","  D. Rail transport"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Rail provides a rough ride for cargo, resulting in more breakage than occurs in cargo transported by truck, water, or air.  "},{"question":"For which of the following items should demand be calculated rather than forecast?","choices":["A. All Chevrolets ","  B. All Chevrolet Cobalts ","  C. All steering wheels for new Chevrolet Cobalts ","  D. All Chevrolet replacement parts"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Steering wheels are a dependent demand item; the demand for dependent items should be calculated from the forecast of demand for their parent items. Steering wheels are a component; the new cars they go into are the parents. Replacement parts are sold, manufactured, and forecast as independent items, not as dependent components.  "},{"question":"Which of the following correctly identifies the deseasonalized monthly demand (to the nearest whole number) for the first half of the calendar year in the example shown in the table below? ","choices":["A. 100 ","  B. 105 ","  C. 186 ","  D. 630 "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The deseasonalized demand is the sum of the seasonal averages divided by the number of \"seasons\" (or months) listed: (100 + 102 + 105 + 106 + 107 + 110) / 6 = 630 / 6 = 105. "},{"question":"Place the following modes of transportation in order of rate per ton-mile for carrying cargo, with I being the lowest rates and IV being the highest.","choices":["I. ","\tRail ","\tII. ","\tAir "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Water transport offers the lowest rates per ton, much lower even than rail, which is second. Trucking is considerably more expensive than rail but substantially less expensive than air "},{"question":"Which one of the following production strategies sometimes meets resistance from distribution centers because of the increased demands for skill training and capacity expansion?","choices":["A. Make-to-order ","  B. JIT ","  C. Assemble-to-order ","  D. Make-to-stock "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"An assemble-to-order strategy may require warehouse or sales personnel to complete the final stages of finishing a product, thus requiring workers to acquire new skills and, in some cases, the facility to expand capacity to accommodate the finishing operations.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is generally considered to be the most responsible strategy for managing reverse logistics?","choices":["A. Accepting product returns for recycling by the manufacturer ","  B. Breaking down returned goods to reuse undamaged components ","  C. Accepting product returns for efficient delivery to a clean landfill ","  D. Reduction of resources used in extraction, manufacture, and packaging "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Reducing use of resources ranks highest in the reverse logistics hierarchy. The other strategies mentioned are also responsible and should be used when options higher up the pyramid are not feasible.  "},{"question":". ","choices":["Expenses involved in the reverse logistics chain may be offset by which of the following?","A. Rebates from landfills ","  B. Freight discounts on shipments of returned items ","  C. Sale of service contracts "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Revenue from the sale of service contracts can offset some of the expenses involved in the reverse logistics chain, including higher transportation fees for small, sporadic shipments; the addition of transportation lanes to reach specialized warehouses; and, of course, the costs to the company of making warranty repairs. "},{"question":"Which of the following might cause cyclical movements in a time series of demand data?","choices":["A. Random changes in consumer sentiment ","  B. Steady decline in buying related to the product cycle ","  C. Recession ","  D. Holiday shopping"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The business cycle correlates with alternating medium-term advances and declines in consumer buying patterns. Cycles are not short-term fluctuations related to holidays or random events, nor are they steady trends in only one direction, such as might be caused by factors such as a product cycle or demographics.  "},{"question":"Which of the following forms the basis for a naive demand forecast?","choices":["A. Market analysis ","  B. Intuition ","  C. Data from the last demand period ","  D. Analogy "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Naive forecasting assumes that demand in the next period will equal demand in the last period. It is a form of quantitative forecasting but lacks any analysis.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following is not allowed in a foreign trade zone?","choices":["A. Performing break-bulk operations to reduce import duties owed ","  B. Storing goods tax-free for an indefinite period of time ","  C. Retail trade ","  D. Repackaging or otherwise altering cargo to remedy potential customs violations "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Retail trade is forbidden inside a foreign trade zone. All the other activities are specifically permitted.  "},{"question":"Basing a demand forecast for kitchen appliances on housing start data is an example of which of the following?","choices":["A. Dependent demand forecasting ","  B. Market analysis ","  C. Extrinsic forecasting ","  D. Pyramid forecasting"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Basing a forecast for a product on data about economic indicators such as housing starts, population trends, or employment statistics is called extrinsic forecasting to distinguish it from intrinsic forecasting based on data about the product itself. Historical analogy bases forecasts for one product on data from a similar (analogous) product, not on data about economic trends. "},{"question":"Capacity and materials are committed to specific orders inside which of the following zones on the master production schedule?","choices":["A. Slushy zone ","  B. Frozen zone ","  C. Liquid zone ","  D. Planning zone"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"When all capacity and materials have been committed to specific orders, a demand time fence may be placed on the MPS, marking off a frozen zone in which no orders can be filled without permission from senior management.  "},{"question":"When international trade is financed with a letter of credit, which of the following entities actually makes the final payment to the seller?","choices":["A. Buyer's bank ","  B. Buyer ","  C. Seller's bank ","  D. Inland export carrier "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The seller (exporter) sends a draft to its banker, who honors it based upon its assurance of reimbursement by the buyer's bank, which in its turn depends upon reimbursement by the buyer (whose money it may already hold on account).  "},{"question":"Which of the following is the type of contract that initiates all foreign shipments?","choices":["A. Export license ","  B. Commercial invoice ","  C. Certificate of origin ","  D. Bill of lading"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"All shipments intended to cross a border are initiated by a bill of lading (B/L). The B/L constitutes the carrier's contract and receipt for the goods to be transported.  "},{"question":"The S\u0026OP planning team might decide to adopt a chase production strategy because it offers which of the following benefits?","choices":["A. Protection against a sudden need to hire temp workers in production ","  B. Reduction of resource costs during demand periods ","  C. More predictable production scheduling ","  D. Reduced inventory holding costs "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The chase production strategy, also called demand matching, attempts to match production to demand in each period of the schedule. If the strategy succeeds, inventory costs can be kept to a minimum. The tradeoffs include possibilities of extra hiring (or layoffs) if demand and production don't match, plus a need to ramp up capacity to match peak demand.  "},{"question":"A business plan would typically include which of the following?","choices":["A. Definition of sales territories ","  B. Clearly defined marketing tactics ","  C. Long-term guidance for developing tactical production plans ","  D. Monthly production figures for each product family "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The business plan provides a long-range view of strategy and guidance for developing tactical plans for sales, marketing, and operations.  "},{"question":"CPFR includes formal guidelines for a growing number of scenarios. Which of the following CPFR scenarios includes such methods as graphical presentations of new products to help make merchandizing decisions in the absence of solid historical data on demand?","choices":["A. Store replenishment collaboration ","  B. DC replenishment collaboration ","  C. Retail event collaboration ","  D. Collaborative assortment planning"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Assortment planning in industries in which demand and product styles change with each season present a special challenge to forecasters. The constant rotation through different styles or models means there is little historical demand data for particular products. VICS CPFR includes a scenario with guidelines for assortment planning based on graphic presentations of new models along with financial models.  "},{"question":"Which of the following has the highest fixed cost of any means of transporting petroleum?","choices":["A. Ships ","  B. Trucks ","  C. Pipelines ","  D. Trains "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Expenses related to construction, right of way, and pumping capacity give pipelines the highest fixed costs of any mode of transporting freight.  "},{"question":"Capacity control takes place against which of the following time horizons?","choices":["A. Everyday activity ","  B. Monthly horizon ","  C. Annual horizon ","  D. Long term "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Capacity control takes place in the very short term in the context of daily production. "},{"question":"According to the ABC system of classifying inventory, an application of the Pareto principle, the greatest share of revenue will be generated by which of the following numbers of inventory items (approximately)?","choices":["A. 80 percent ","  B. 55 percent ","  C. 30 percent ","  D. 15 percent"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The ABC system of classifying inventory asserts that the A items in your inventory will constitute only about 15 percent of the total number of items but will create 70 to 80 percent of value. This is an approximate application of the Pareto principle, or 80-20 rule, which holds that about 20 percent of possible causes account for about 80 percent of outcomes.  "},{"question":"Which of the following institutions publishes the \"Orange Book\" containing recommendations that form the basis of international dangerous goods (hazardous materials) laws and regulations?","choices":["A. World Court ","  B. United Nations ","  C. International Maritime Association ","  D. International Chamber of Commerce (ICC) "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The \"Orange Book\" is published by the United Nations; its first edition came out in 1956. It contains the United Nations Recommendations on the Transport of Dangerous Goods (UNRMTDG), in which all national controls are grounded. The UN recommendations do not have the force of law, but national regulations based on them may.  "},{"question":"Which of the following conditions is generally associated with lot-for-lot order sizing?","choices":["A. Small, frequent orders ","  B. Independent demand items ","  C. Large batches ","  D. Safety stock buffers"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Lot-for-lot sizing is typically used with small, frequent deliveries of dependent demand items. Longer time buckets and larger order sizes are more likely to require a buffer of safety stock.  "},{"question":"Which of the following design philosophies is most responsible for furniture that comes in kit form to be assembled by the retail customer at home?","choices":["A. Concurrent engineering ","  B. Design for the environment ","  C. Design for logistics ","  D. Design for manufacture "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Designing products in kit form makes them easier to transport, store, and package, all aspects of logistics. "},{"question":"Which of the following modes of carrying cargo requires the least durable packaging?","choices":["A. Inland water carriage ","  B. Ocean shipping ","  C. Air ","  D. Rail "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Air transport subjects cargo to the least likelihood of damage en route. It places the most restrictions on the weight of packaging, so it both allows and requires the least durable packaging "},{"question":"A hard drive that can be used in many different kinds of computers is an example of which of the following design strategies?","choices":["A. Modular design ","  B. Standardization ","  C. Integral design ","  D. Universality "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A hard drive is a module that, along with other modules, can be mixed and matched to assemble computers with many different features.  "},{"question":"Inventory held to cover transit time is called which of the following?","choices":["A. Work-in-process inventory ","  B. Anticipatory inventory ","  C. Fluctuation inventory ","  D. Pipeline inventory"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Pipeline inventory is stock kept on hand to fill orders while the next lot is in transit. It is also known as transportation inventory.  "},{"question":"Which of the following correctly describes the benefit of conducting periodic inventory counts?","choices":["A. Periodic counting is inexpensive. ","  B. Periodic counting provides a financial value for all inventory at one point in time. ","  C. Periodic counts don't disrupt the ordinary flow of business. ","  D. Periodic counting promotes accurate ordering. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Periodic inventory counts provide a value for inventory at one point in time, but they disrupt business, are relatively expensive, are prone to inaccuracy, and don't promote accurate ordering policies (because they are infrequent and tend to be inaccurate).  "},{"question":"Lead time can be determined from the information in which of the following?","choices":["A. Work center file ","  B. Routing file ","  C. Open order file ","  D. Both a and b"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The routing and work center files contain all the times necessary to calculate the total lead time. "},{"question":"The impact of seasonality on demand in a fast-food restaurant might be measured in which of the following ways?","choices":["A. Time of year ","  B. Day of the week ","  C. Hour of the day ","  D. All of the above"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"As a demand planning concept, \"seasonality\" refers to demand patterns influenced by time, not just by the four seasons of the year. The restaurant business varies with the calendar, the day of the week, and the time of day.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following conditions is a potential drawback of lot-for-lot order sizing?","choices":["A. High setup costs ","  B. Incompatibility with JIT ","  C. High inventory costs ","  D. Inventory build-up "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Typically used with JIT, lot-for-lot sizing delivers the exact amount needed when it is needed, thereby eliminating inventory buffers. Frequent delivery of small lots requires more setups.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a riderless material-handling device that moves along optical tape or magnetic wire in the floor?","choices":["A. Automated storage and retrieval system (AS/RS) ","  B. Automated guided vehicle system (AGVS) ","  C. Automated sorting device ","  D. Radio-controlled crane truck"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Automated guided vehicle systems (AGVS) ride along magnetic wire or optical tape. They are fully programmable, require no rider, and can be equipped with forks. "},{"question":"Which of the following smoothing constants would yield the same result as a naive forecast?","choices":["A. 0.01 ","  B. 0.05 ","  C. 0.50 ","  D. 1.0"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Smoothing constants are generally chosen between 0.05 and 0.50. A constant of 0 would give the same forecast as for the previous month, because it would eliminate the portion of the equation including the forecast error. A constant of 1.0 would yield a forecast equal to the current month's demand; in the equation, the forecast numbers would cancel out, leaving only the actual demand amount. In between 0 and 1, the constant determines how much weight you give to the forecast error.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following warehouse operations would take place at a manufacturer's centralized warehouse to facilitate delivery of one product to many retailers?","choices":["A. Break-bulk ","  B. Spot stocking ","  C. Consolidation ","  D. Mixing"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Break-bulk operations break an incoming shipment from one source into smaller lots for reshipping to specific customers. "},{"question":"Which of the following correctly identifies the MAD for the six months in the example shown in the table below? ","choices":["A. -8.00 ","  B. 1.67 ","  C. 2.00 ","  D. 12.00"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The MAD (mean absolute deviation) is the average amount by which the forecast differs from the actual demand (Deviation = Demand - Forecast). It is \"absolute\" because it takes into account only the amount of the deviation, not the direction. Tracking the absolute deviation provides information for use in assessing the reliability of forecasts.  "},{"question":"For make-to-stock production of an integral design, the master production schedule includes production dates for which of the following?","choices":["A. Components ","  B. Orders ","  C. End items ","  D. Product families "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The master production schedule includes dates of production for make-to-stock end items. (This can be either finished products or, in a modular approach, components.)  "},{"question":"Which of the following identifies a risk of ordering more inventory than required to fill forecast orders?","choices":["A. Higher per-car costs for transporting the inventory ","  B. Increased obsolescence ","  C. Higher per-item costs for purchasing the inventory ","  D. Decoupling from supplier"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The risk of having inventory items become obsolete increases when amounts ordered exceed the forecast significantly. Economies of scale in transport and purchase are potential benefits of larger orders, as is decoupling from the supplier.  "},{"question":"Which of the following may increase as a tradeoff when a logistics chain institutes risk pooling by moving inventory from several smaller warehouses to a larger central storage facility?","choices":["A. Total amount of inventory held at one time ","  B. Inventory handling costs ","  C. Number of stockouts ","  D. Delivery lead times"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Risk pooling is a means of reducing the risk of stockouts by consolidating inventory in a central warehouse. With a larger store of goods in the central warehouse, even the largest, unexpected order will have less chance of exhausting the inventory, as it might in a smaller warehouse. With fewer facilities adding safety stock to their orders (plus the lower stockout risk), the total amount of inventory can be reduced, and less inventory means lower holding and handling expenses. Lead times may go up, however, for deliveries made to customers that are more distant from the central warehouse than from the smaller facilities it replaced.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following processes results in production numbers driven by dependent demand?","choices":["A. Master production scheduling process ","  B. Material requirements planning process ","  C. Market planning process ","  D. Sales and operations planning process"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The MRP schedules delivery of dependent demand items (which are in turn based upon independent demand forecasts). The other processes work with independent demand or product families.  "},{"question":"Which of the following could appear in a planning bill of materials?","choices":["A. All the #10 nails intended for delivery to a chain of home improvement stores ","  B. All the parts required to produce a component for use in mass customization ","  C. All the transistors to be used in assembling a variety of electronics components ","  D. All the parts necessary to manufacture one car radio "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A planning bill of materials includes small items intended for use in a variety of finished items. They are ordered in bulk for convenience and economies of scale even though they have no one parent to list on a regular bill of materials.  "},{"question":"Which of the following processes includes the disaggregation of product families?","choices":["A. Operations planning ","  B. Resource requirements planning ","  C. Sales planning ","  D. Master production scheduling "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Disaggregation takes place during the development of the master production schedule.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following warehouse operations is most appropriate for a manufacturer that receives components from many suppliers and wants to achieve economies of scale when transporting those components to one plant?","choices":["A. Cross-dock ","  B. Consolidation ","  C. Mixing ","  D. Break-bulk"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"To achieve economies of scale in transportation, consolidation combines shipments from many incoming sources when loading outbound vehicles headed for a single location.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following is the most significant drawback of specialized package carriers such as FedEx and DHL?","choices":["A. Lack of multimodal capability ","  B. Too expensive for small businesses to use economically ","  C. Lack of flexibility in pickup and delivery locations ","  D. Price"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"With their intermodal networks, FedEx, UPS, and DHL offer door-to-door delivery on rapid timetables, but they are not inexpensive. As delivery services, they are perhaps best used when speed is more important than price. Many express services offer logistics consultation and total logistics management (4PL) and are capable of providing small businesses the benefit of economies of scale and deep logistics expertise.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is an input to rough-cut capacity planning (RCCP)?","choices":["A. Master schedule ","  B. Weekly output per end item ","  C. Weekly output per component ","  D. Aggregate output per product family "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"RCCP determines if resources are available (or can be made available) in the network to achieve the goals in the master schedule.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following represents a sound approach to tracking data to use in demand forecasting?","choices":["A. Include all product options. ","  B. Exclude consideration of competitors' activities. ","  C. Include data by ship date, not order date. ","  D. Exclude cancellations and returns. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Forecast data should include demand for all product options as well as total demand for the product. You want to know when items were in demand, not when they were shipped. Competitors' product introductions are likely to affect your forecasts. Returns and cancellations should be subtracted from orders when calculating actual demand.  "},{"question":"Referring to the demand table below, calculate a three-month weighted moving average forecast for April using a 3-2-1 weighting for March, February, and January, respectively. Which of the following identifies the correct forecast for April using this method? ","choices":["A. 20.17 ","  B. 20.33 ","  C. 20.67 ","  D. 40.33"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The three-month weighted moving average forecast for April is 20.17 (3 x 22 = 66; 2 x 17 = 34; 1 x 21 = 21; 66 + 34 + 21 = 121; 121 / 6 = 20.17). Did you remember to divide by the sum of the weights (6) instead of by 3?  "},{"question":"Which of the following constitutes a potentially appropriate way to segment a market?","choices":["A. Geography ","  B. Market potential ","  C. Age ","  D. Any of the above can be appropriate."],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Market segmentation and the deployment of the sales force can be based upon any of a number of criteria, including but by no means limited to geography, market potential, or age.  "},{"question":"When engaging the services of a fourth-party logistics provider, a logistics manager should be careful to minimize the effects of which of the following potential risks?","choices":["A. Reduction in flexible deployment of resources ","  B. Reduced economies of scale ","  C. Reduction in control ","  D. Less rapid adjustment to new customer technologies "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Transferring responsibility for logistics to a 4PL involves loss of control, so a manager may want to compensate with frequent reviews (at least at first). The upside of giving control of logistics to a specialist should be an increase in flexibility, greater economies of scale, and more advanced logistics technology. "},{"question":"Which of the following would provide a sound method for grouping products into product families for the operations plan?","choices":["A. Similar seasonality ","  B. Similarity of manufacturing processes ","  C. National market destination ","  D. Appeal to a particular age group "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Product families for purposes of the operations plan are best chosen by similar manufacturing requirements to facilitate other planning processes, such as production scheduling. (Marketing can group products in other ways for its purposes.)  "},{"question":"When a logistics manager removes a complete echelon from the distribution chain to reduce overall expenses, there may be a tradeoff for expenses in which of the following areas?","choices":["A. Increased transportation costs for extra miles of carriage ","  B. Increased inventory handling costs ","  C. Increased taxes on property and equipment ","  D. Increased inventory holding costs "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Removing an echelon from the network should reduce all the costs specified in the options except for transportation costs. Removing one level of warehousing, for example, will most likely increase the number of miles goods are carried from the points upstream from the echelon to the points downstream.  "},{"question":"Which of the following design strategies offers streamlined production and lower purchasing costs with a possible tradeoff against reduced design flexibility and lower quality?","choices":["A. Component commonality ","  B. Universality ","  C. Mass customization ","  D. Integral design "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Using common components for a variety of purposes provides economies of scale in purchasing and manufacture but can limit design flexibility and reduce quality.  "},{"question":"Which of the following provides a point of reference for formulating the sales and operations plan?","choices":["A. Production forecast ","  B. Financial plan ","  C. Business plan ","  D. Marketing plan "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The sales and operations plan takes the business plan as its point of reference for developing a plan that balances supply and demand by merging input from sales and marketing on the one hand and operations on the other.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a type of supply chain collaboration formalized by the Voluntary Interindustry Commerce Standards Association (VICS)?","choices":["A. Quick response ","  B. Continuous replenishment ","  C. Vendor-managed inventory ","  D. Collective planning, forecasting, and replenishment"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Collaborative planning, forecasting, and replenishment (CPFR®) is a formal description of best practices developed and maintained by VICS to help supply chain partners develop successful collaborations. "},{"question":"Which one of the following describes the typical situation in regards to payment of import duties?","choices":["A. The exporter determines the tariff classification and the importer pays the duty. ","  B. The importer determines the tariff classification and the exporter pays the duty. ","  C. The importer determines the tariff classification and pays the duty. ","  D. The exporter determines the tariff classification and pays the duty. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The exporter determines the tariff classification using the harmonized code when packaging the goods for export. The importer (usually through the customs house broker) pays the duty when goods come through customs.  "},{"question":"Which of the following documents is used to bolster an importer's claims for favorable import duty rates granted by treaty to the exporter's country?","choices":["A. Export B/L ","  B. Letter of credit ","  C. Consular invoice ","  D. Certificate of origin"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"A certificate of origin states that the cargo originated in the exporter's country and is therefore eligible for the favorable import duty granted to goods originating in that country. To qualify for the lowest rates, importers sometimes have their purchases shipped from the country of origin through a country qualifying for more favorable rates and then reexported to their own country. The country of origin is the place in which the goods in question last underwent a significant transformation, not the country from which they were shipped.  "},{"question":"Which of the following would be a typical time horizon for sales and operations planning?","choices":["A. One week to one month ","  B. One month to one quarter ","  C. 12 to 18 months ","  D. 18 months to three years "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The sales and operations plan typically extends out at least a year and no more than 18 months and involves both short- and medium-term planning.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following is a negotiable certificate of ownership?","choices":["A. Straight B/L ","  B. Order B/L ","  C. Dock receipt ","  D. Air waybill "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Order B/Ls can be used to transfer ownership of cargo. Straight B/Ls (including air bills) document cargo intended for delivery straight to the buyer without intermediate title transfers.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following actions would be appropriate if the load scheduled for a work site exceeds its rated capacity?","choices":["A. Reduce workers' hours to save money. ","  B. Shift work to another work center with available capacity. ","  C. Order more safety stock. ","  D. Lay off workers."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"If a work center has more load than capacity, shifting work to another center is one possible way to restore the balance (if another center is available and has excess capacity). You can also increase available time (more workers, machines, or hours of work) or increase efficiency.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following would you select to move pallets through warehouse aisles while minimizing costs?","choices":["A. Automated towlines ","  B. Conveyer belt ","  C. Tow tractors with trailers ","  D. Forklift truck"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The conveyer belt has no operator, so it not only minimizes operator costs, it eliminates them. Automated towlines are not likely to appeal to the cost-conscious manager.  "},{"question":"Which of the following items makes up the majority of rail cargo in the United States and Great Britain?","choices":["A. Heavy industrial products, such as automobiles and equipment ","  B. Coal ","  C. Agricultural commodities ","  D. Forest products "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Coal makes up the bulk of rail cargo in both the United States and Great Britain. Rail transport is most appropriate for heavy, durable items of low value like raw materials, agricultural products, chemicals, construction materials, and industrial metals.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements correctly identifies the major purpose of the sales and operations plan (S\u0026OP)?","choices":["A. S\u0026OP represents the firm's essential planning document for use in securing startup financing from bankers and investors. ","  B. S\u0026OP represents the first pass at balancing sales and output of end items. ","  C. S\u0026OP represents the mutual agreement of finance, sales, marketing, operations, and senior management on a single set of supply/demand numbers. ","  D. S\u0026OP represents the essence of a contract between sales and operations."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The sales and operations plan reconciles the business plans of all units of the firm, including finance, sales and marketing, and operations; the unified set of numbers has the approval of senior management. It is neither a contract between sales and operations nor a balance of end item supply and demand.  "},{"question":"Which of the following numbers is the correct seasonal average demand for February in the example shown in the table below (rounded to the nearest whole number)? ","choices":["A. 99 ","  B. 100 ","  C. 102 ","  D. 105 "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The seasonal average demand for February is the monthly average demand for the three Februarys listed: (101 + 101 + 105) / 3 = 102.  "},{"question":"Which of the following parties determines the tariff classification of an import?","choices":["A. Exporter ","  B. Customs ","  C. World Trade Organization inspectors ","  D. Importer"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The exporter bears responsibility for determining the classification of the goods it sells in international transactions. It does so by reference to the harmonized tariff codes.  "},{"question":"The exporter takes the most risk in which of the following export-import financing arrangements?","choices":["A. Buyer's payment from an open account ","  B. Consignment of goods ","  C. Seller's credit ","  D. Letter of credit"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"In seller's credit financing, the seller (exporter) accepts the importer's credit card (or other promise to pay) and thus takes the most financial risk involved in any of options described.  "},{"question":"The master schedule shows inventory on hand of 150 items, scheduled production of 500 items, and booked orders of 400 items. Which of the following is the correct number of available-to-promise items?","choices":["A. 150 ","  B. 250 ","  C. 500 ","  D. 650 "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Available-to-promise equals the inventory on hand plus scheduled production reduced by orders already on the books. The ATP continues to decline as orders come in during the period. "},{"question":"In the economic order quantity calculation, which one of the following statements most accurately identifies the effect of increasing order sizes on inventory holding and order costs?","choices":["A. Holding costs remain constant while setup costs rise steadily. ","  B. Total costs drop up to a point and then rise steadily. ","  C. Economies of scale lower all holding and ordering/setup costs equally and steadily. ","  D. Setup and order costs remain constant while holding costs drop steadily. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The larger the order, the higher the holding costs, because there is more inventory to hold. Setup costs tend to go down as orders grow larger because of economies of scale. (Larger orders can be placed less frequently than smaller orders, thus reducing the number of setups.)  "},{"question":"The sales and operations plan would include which of the following?","choices":["A. Monthly production figures by individual manufacturing center ","  B. Weekly production figures by individual SKU ","  C. Monthly production figures by product family ","  D. Monthly production figures for individual SKUs"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"S\u0026OP focuses on monthly production amounts for product families. Scheduling for individual products (SKUs) comes later in the planning process.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following functional areas is responsible for demand forecasting?","choices":["A. Purchasing ","  B. Executive team ","  C. IT ","  D. Sales and marketing "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The sales and marketing area is responsible and accountable for forecasting. Someone has to be responsible for the forecast for assessment purposes, but this does not mean that other areas cannot contribute to the forecast or that the forecast cannot be shared with other functional areas and supply chain partners. Information sharing is key to supply chain management.  "},{"question":"Which of the following collaborations has increasingly evolved from the traditional relationship of supplier as seller and retailer as buyer into a consignment-sales arrangement in which the supplier owns the goods until the end customer buys them?","choices":["A. Continuous replenishment ","  B. Rapid replenishment ","  C. Quick replenishment ","  D. Vendor-managed inventory (VMI)"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"VMI, a more sophisticated partnership than CR (also known as RR) and QR, has increasingly tended to involve consignment sales.  "},{"question":"If you favored a push approach to managing a supply chain, which of the following production strategies would you be most likely to adopt?","choices":["A. JIT ","  B. Assemble-to-order ","  C. Make-to-stock ","  D. Make-to-order"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A make-to-stock strategy \"pushes\" materials and products through the system in accordance with preset schedules rather than letting them be \"pulled\" through by actual orders "},{"question":"Which of the following constitutes the primary reason for a supplier to agree to sell goods on consignment rather than selling to its customers for resale to the customer's customers?","choices":["A. Decreased setup costs ","  B. Decreased labor costs ","  C. Decreased inventory holding costs ","  D. Greater visibility of inventory management"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"In VMI, both partners benefit from increased visibility of the inventory management process, because they share information about retail demand on the one hand and supplier processes on the other. Setup and holding costs increase for the supplier, however, though they should decrease overall as forecasting improves.  "},{"question":"According to the familiar Incoterm FOB, which one of the following entities holds title to export/import cargo once it has \"passed over the ship's rail\"?","choices":["A. Importer ","  B. Carrier ","  C. Exporter ","  D. Insurance company "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Once the cargo has \"passed over the ship's rail\" (to use the original terms), the importer takes title and is responsible for insurance, etc. The Incoterm stands for \"Free on Board\" (free, that is, from the exporter's point of view).  "},{"question":"Which of the following identifies a type of collaboration in which a manufacturer of razor blades determines how its product is displayed on a retailer's shelves and performs cycle counting at the store?","choices":["A. Vendor-managed inventory (VMI) ","  B. Quick response (QR) ","  C. Continuous replenishment (CR) ","  D. Collaborative planning, forecasting, and replenishment (CPFR)"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"VMI (vendor-managed inventory) is a form of collaboration in which a supplier performs some or all of the inventory operations traditionally handled by a retailer, including display design, replenishment, inventory counting, record keeping, and so on. (VMI can overlap with other systems.)  "},{"question":"The forecasting method known as the pyramid technique specifically incorporates which one of the following principles of forecasting?","choices":["A. Short-range forecasts are more reliable than long-range forecasts. ","  B. Product group forecasts are more reliable than single-product forecasts. ","  C. Forecasts are always wrong. ","  D. Quantitative data are preferable to qualitative estimates. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Product group forecasts are more reliable than single-product forecasts, so the pyramid technique begins by forecasting demand for the product family and then disaggregates the demand to generate single-product demand forecasts. This ensures alignment between forecasts for the group and the components of the group. (This is not to imply that the technique ignores other principles, only that it specifically relies upon the superior reliability of group forecasting.)  "},{"question":"The marketing department's involvement with product management includes which of the following phases of the product's life cycle?","choices":["A. Development through introduction ","  B. Introduction only ","  C. Conception through maturity ","  D. All phases, from conception through withdrawal"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Marketing can play a useful role in planning, tracking, and managing demand from the beginning to the end of the life cycle.  "},{"question":"Which of the following design strategies is the polar opposite of integral design?","choices":["A. Modular design ","  B. Design for postponement ","  C. Universality ","  D. Mass customization"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Modular design creates mix-and-match components that can be combined into different products, whereas integral design creates one product from a unique set of components.  "},{"question":"Which of the following objectives was most important in traditional warehousing (before World War II)?","choices":["A. Market presence ","  B. Rapid response ","  C. Minimizing inventory amounts ","  D. Full support throughout product life cycles"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Marketing concerns drove the traditional warehousing strategy of placing a warehouse near each market and stocking it with sufficient inventory to ensure uninterrupted order fulfillment. Postwar growth of sophisticated logistics has added the other objectives.  "},{"question":"Which of the following might a logistics manager choose to carry raw materials in local markets at a relatively low rate determined by the market?","choices":["A. Contract carrier ","  B. Private carrier ","  C. Common carrier ","  D. Exempt carrier"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Exempt carriers are (as the name suggests) granted exemption from economic regulation if they carry certain types of products, including unprocessed agricultural products and raw materials. They generally operate locally and charge relatively low rates based on the going rates in their markets. "},{"question":"Which one of the following warehouse operations assumes no storage of incoming goods before reshipping?","choices":["A. Mixing ","  B. Assembly-to-order ","  C. Spot stocking ","  D. Break-bulk"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"In break-bulk operations, the incoming shipment moves straight through the warehouse to be broken down on the dock and reshipped. "},{"question":"Pick-to-light systems speed inventory retrieval when used in conjunction with which of the following material-handling equipment?","choices":["A. Carousels ","  B. Automatic sorting devices ","  C. Automated storage and retrieval system (AS/RS) ","  D. Automated conveyers"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Pick-to-light systems add lights to carousels to provide information such as the location and number of items to retrieve.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following firms, known in Japan as sogo shosha, may be a large conglomerate that actually buys goods in one country for sale in a foreign market?","choices":["A. Ship broker ","  B. Export trading company (ETC) ","  C. Consolidator ","  D. Foreign carrier "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"An ETC (export trading company) buys goods domestically to sell into foreign markets. Such firms are especially significant in Japan, where they may own steamship lines, warehouses, insurance services, and so forth.  "},{"question":"Which of the following features was a drawback in the early versions of MRP software?","choices":["A. Failed to include component lead times ","  B. Assumed infinite capacity ","  C. Made extra work for the scheduler ","  D. Lacked an automated bill of materials"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The earliest versions of MRP software assumed infinite capacity and therefore would sometimes create impossible schedules.  "},{"question":"Which of the following design strategies would most likely be responsible for the fact that only one screwdriver is needed to remove all the screws securing a computer case and to unfasten all components from the motherboard inside?","choices":["A. Design for manufacture ","  B. Green engineering ","  C. Design for logistics ","  D. Component commonality"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Component commonality is the design strategy of substituting one common component for a variety of similar components.  "},{"question":"As measured by ton-miles per years, which of the following modes of transportation moves the most cargo in the United States?","choices":["A. Truck ","  B. Water ","  C. Pipeline ","  D. Rail "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"In the United States, trucks move the largest amount of commercial cargo as measured by ton-miles per year. Trucks also move the most cargo as measured by tons and cargo value.  "},{"question":"Which of the following would contain information such as queue time and machine setup time?","choices":["A. Component bill of materials ","  B. Route sheet ","  C. Master production schedule ","  D. Order release form "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The route sheet lists the work centers a component passes through in temporal order along with the operations performed at each work center and the time spent in queues, etc.  "},{"question":"In general, the largest portion of a product's delivery cost can be attributed to which of the following?","choices":["A. Transportation ","  B. Product design ","  C. Production/assembly ","  D. Handling"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"As much as 70 percent of a product's delivery cost is attributable to its design.  "},{"question":"When deciding whether to acquire a component from a domestic or foreign source, which of the following comparisons provides the most accurate assessment of their relative value?","choices":["A. Simple price comparison ","  B. Relative price plus transportation ","  C. Relative price adjusted for currency exchange and import duties ","  D. Landed cost of each"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Landed cost includes every expense involved in acquiring a component (or any item of value) and bringing it to your dock, including price, transportation, fees and commissions, import duties, etc.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is the primary focus of the master production schedule?","choices":["A. Monthly aggregate production amounts for end items ","  B. Weekly aggregate production amounts for product families ","  C. Monthly aggregate production amounts for product families ","  D. Weekly production amounts for individual products "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The focus of MPS is on weekly scheduling for individual products. You could derive the other amounts from the master schedule.  "},{"question":"Which of the following would be included in a list of dependent demand items?","choices":["A. Shirts delivered to a retailer for stocking on shelves ","  B. Computer hard drives delivered to a manufacturer for installation in new computers ","  C. Computer audio subsystems delivered to a computer superstore for sale as upgrade items ","  D. GPS systems delivered to an auto production plant for installation in new cars "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Dependent demand items are components delivered for installation in finished products. The same items may also be subject to independent demand when, like hard drives in the option above, they are sold separately for purchase in repair operations or as upgrades. If the item is ordered directly by the consumer, it is part of independent demand; if it is ordered for installation in a parent product only, it is the subject of dependent demand.  "},{"question":"A dock receipt is issued by which of the following?","choices":["A. Importer (or banker) receiving a shipment ","  B. Ship agent ","  C. Customs officer ","  D. Customs house agent "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The ship agent issues a dock certificate to signify that the steamship company has received cargo brought to port by the inland carrier.  "},{"question":"A shipper whose exports are carried from the foreign port to the importer's dock by trucks that return empty to the port might hire which one of the following firms to find goods to carry on the backhaul route?","choices":["A. Non-vessel operating common carrier (NVOCC) ","  B. Freight forwarder ","  C. Export packager ","  D. Consolidator "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Consolidators specialize in filling trucks for backhaul journeys from import destinations to port when the importer provides no goods for carriage. The consolidator may have to consolidate small shipments from a number of exporters to fill the carriers.  "},{"question":"Flexible scheduling is most likely to be a priority for which of the following transportation stakeholders?","choices":["A. Carrier ","  B. Shipper ","  C. Consignee ","  D. Both shipper and consignee "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Shippers and consignees both want scheduling that suits their particular timing needs, whereas carriers tend to value stability. Hence the higher prices for services such as next-day air. "},{"question":"Which one of the following describes the main drawback of the crane truck?","choices":["A. High fixed cost ","  B. Lack of flexibility compared to forklifts ","  C. High operator costs ","  D. Requirement of wide aisles for maneuverability "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Crane trucks (or stacker cranes) are capital-intensive purchases, but they are available in driverless models to eliminate operator costs. They offer similar flexibility to forklifts and can move through narrow aisles. "},{"question":"A logistics manager might approach which one of the following intermediaries to purchase cargo space that the firm purchased elsewhere and marked up for resale?","choices":["A. Export trading company (ETC) ","  B. Freight forwarder ","  C. Consolidator ","  D. Non-vessel operating common carrier (NVOCC)"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"An NVOCC (non-vessel operating common carrier) buys cargo space on a carrier to resell to shippers.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following conditions contributes to the supply chain phenomenon known as the bullwhip effect?","choices":["A. JIT production strategies ","  B. Inaccurate demand forecasting ","  C. Shortened lead times  ","  D. Insufficient batch sizes "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"A major contributor to the bullwhip effect is inaccuracy in demand forecasting, which can lead to ordering too much or too little stock, thus contributing to the effect's exaggerated peaks and valleys of demand.  "},{"question":"Which of the following modes of transportation is most appropriate for carrying small, highly valuable, fragile or perishable cargo?","choices":["A. Water ","  B. Road ","  C. Air ","  D. Rail "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Air transport is especially appropriate for high-value items because it is relatively secure, smooth, and rapid.  "},{"question":"How often, under normal circumstances, does a pre-S\u0026OP meeting take place?","choices":["A. Weekly ","  B. Monthly ","  C. Quarterly ","  D. Annually"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Sales and operations planning (S\u0026OP) is a monthly process.  "},{"question":"If you are making up a production schedule using the lot-for-lot sizing method, which of the following equations would you use to determine the planned order receipt (assuming you know the gross amount required)?","choices":["A. Gross requirement alone ","  B. Gross requirement minus projected amounts on hand ","  C. Gross requirement minus scheduled receipts ","  D. Gross requirement minus projected on hand minus scheduled receipts "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"In a lot-for-lot schedule, the planned order release is equal to net requirements (gross requirement reduced by any inventory on hand). There is unlikely to be inventory on hand except at the beginning of an order period.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following correctly identifies the membership of shipping associations?","choices":["A. Small ship owners seeking to compete with larger carriers ","  B. Ship brokers banded together to hire lobbyists to seek regulatory relief from governments around the world ","  C. Smaller export firms seeking discounted rates ","  D. Ocean carriers of all sizes seeking benefits from membership in an industry association "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Shipping associations are groups of smaller exporters seeking to negotiate favorable rates with carriers. Since deregulation, carriers and larger shippers have been able to negotiate private rate agreements that are not disclosed for other exporters' information. Smaller shippers want to benefit from the same discounts but lack the size to negotiate successfully on their own.  "},{"question":"A demand forecast determined by a panel of all the salespeople in an organization may reach an exaggerated, false conclusion by relying on which of the following?","choices":["A. Collective view of their markets ","  B. Personal experience ","  C. Bandwagon effect ","  D. Intuition"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The \"bandwagon effect\" (also called \"groupthink\") can distort the conclusions of a panel if a strong leader emerges with a convincing but wrong-headed view, or if all participants reinforce one another in reaching an exaggerated conclusion. An entire sales force acting in concert may, however, benefit from experience, collective knowledge of the broad market served by the organization, and even intuition.  "},{"question":"If you were able to get a 20 percent discount on any of the following logistics expenses, which would you choose to receive the maximum cost savings?","choices":["A. Transportation ","  B. Compliance ","  C. Materials handling ","  D. Warehousing"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Transportation expenses make up the largest portion of the logistics budget, so taking the discount on transportation costs would give you the largest cost reduction. (Of course, you would have to consider possible tradeoffs if discounting transportation caused cost increases elsewhere in the system.)  "},{"question":"Which of the following numbers gives the correct March forecast using the data below and the exponential smoothing approach? ","choices":["A. 10,100 ","  B. 10,110 ","  C. 10,120 ","  D. 10,150 "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The forecast is 10,100 if you use the exponential smoothing equation as follows: Forecast = Previous Forecast + α (Demand - Forecast), where α is the smoothing constant, or, in this instance, the forecast = 10,150 + .20 (9,900 - 10,150) = 10,100. (Demand for February is 9,900, or sales minus refunds.)  "},{"question":"Which one of the following statements identifies a beneficial result of including more periods in a moving average?","choices":["A. Forecasting becomes more sensitive to cyclical changes. ","  B. Forecasts don't lag so far behind sales data. ","  C. The impact of random variations is reduced. ","  D. Forecasts are more sensitive to trends in demand. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Including more periods in the calculation (six or 12 months instead of three, for example) further reduces the effects of random variation. This is the only benefit. Otherwise, the data gathering and calculations become more difficult and the forecasts lag farther behind changes in demand, making the forecasts less sensitive to trends and cycles.  "},{"question":"To be most effective, design of a reverse logistics chain should begin during which of the following phases of the product life cycle?","choices":["A. Product design ","  B. Introduction ","  C. Maturity ","  D. Decline"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Product design should take reverse logistics into account by considering use of resources, potential for reuse, recycling, etc.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following material-handling devices would you purchase to get the maximum storage density per square foot of warehouse space?","choices":["A. Forklift ","  B. Automated storage and retrieval system (AS/RS) ","  C. Bridge crane ","  D. Automated guided vehicle system (AGVS)"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The automated storage and retrieval system (AS/RS) moves both horizontally and vertically, and it can make the maximum use of floor space by lifting items into (and out of) very high storage racks.  "},{"question":"If you know the actual output of a work center and want to calculate its efficiency, you also need to know which of the following?","choices":["A. Available time ","  B. Number of workers or machines ","  C. Standard expected hours of output ","  D. Utilization"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The efficiency of a work center is the ratio of actual output to standard expected output; in other words, it's a measure of how well the work center is producing in relation to what it can reasonably be expected to produce.  "},{"question":"Considering the types of cargo typically carried over long distances by inland water carrier and the rates per ton-mile, which of the following modes of transportation is the barge's closest competitor?","choices":["A. Piggyback ","  B. Pipeline ","  C. Rail ","  D. Trucking"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Railroad and barges both specialize in carrying very heavy, dense, low-value cargo over long distances. A rail line laid along a waterway would make a potent rival for the water carrier.  "},{"question":"Using the bill of materials to deduct component quantities from inventory as soon as a unit has been manufactured is called which of the following?","choices":["A. Offsetting ","  B. Pegging ","  C. Backflushing ","  D. Bucket reduction"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Backflushing is the use of the bill of materials to eliminate a component from inventory as soon as the parent unit has been manufactured. Backflushing is used in connection with JIT, and it does assume the reduction or elimination of time buckets in scheduling.  "},{"question":"According to the World Trade Organization, which of the following is the right amount to use when declaring the value of imported goods?","choices":["A. Amount stated in the harmonized code for the goods in the cargo ","  B. Calculated market value ","  C. Actual price to the importer ","  D. Exporter's cost plus transaction expenses "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The price paid (or scheduled to be paid) by the importer is the right amount to use when declaring the value of an import. The WTO does permit other \"reasonable\" methods of valuation if circumstances warrant.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements correctly identifies the purpose of the weights in a weighted moving average?","choices":["A. To be more sensitive to recent trends in demand ","  B. To put more emphasis on long-term influences on demand ","  C. To make data gathering and forecasting calculations simpler ","  D. To take account of mean average deviation"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A weighted moving average puts more emphasis than a simple moving average does on the most recent demand numbers. Because of the weighting, it doesn't lag as far behind demand data as a simple moving average. Its focus, therefore, is on recent trends, not the long term. It isn't simpler. "},{"question":"Which of the following forecast techniques relies upon an expert panel that responds to questionnaires and never meets face to face?","choices":["A. Delphi method ","  B. Historical analogy ","  C. Pyramid forecasting ","  D. Sales force consensus forecasting"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The Delphi method uses information from a panel of experts who respond anonymously to questionnaires. After several rounds of responses and critiques, a moderator produces a report expressing the collective opinion of the group.  "},{"question":"How frequently does a firm update S\u0026OP data?","choices":["A. Continuously ","  B. Daily ","  C. Monthly ","  D. Quarterly "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Data are updated as quickly as possible after the end of the month as part of the regular S\u0026OP process.  "},{"question":"Which of the following documents constitutes a price quote in export-import trade?","choices":["A. Pro forma commercial invoice ","  B. Consular invoice ","  C. Dock receipt ","  D. Commercial invoice"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A pro forma commercial invoice, constituting a price quote, may be filled out and sent before a deal has been struck between an exporter and a potential buyer. The buyer (importer) can use the pro forma commercial invoice when securing a letter of credit with its banker.  "},{"question":"Which of the following production strategies is sometimes called mass customization?","choices":["A. Assemble-to-order ","  B. Make-to-order ","  C. Make-to-stock ","  D. Lean production"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The assemble-to-order strategy incorporates some of the benefits of mass production and some of the benefits of true customization by mass-producing components that can be assembled into one of several different versions of a product after receipt of an order.  "},{"question":"Use of a fixed order quantity model is most likely to be effective in which of the following cases?","choices":["A. Shipper is looking for quantity discounts. ","  B. Lead time is highly variable. ","  C. Production is run on lean assumptions. ","  D. Demand is highly unpredictable and light."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Fixed quantity ordering is generally used to fill containers, qualify for quantity discounts, or both. The model works best when demand is known and stable with predictable lead times.  "},{"question":"Which of the following often accompanies goods that are intended to travel in sealed containers across borders, including goods intended only to be admitted temporarily for use in events such as tradeshows?","choices":["A. Bill of lading ","  B. ATA Carnet ","  C. Consular invoice ","  D. Order waybill "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The Carnet, or ATA Carnet, was originally intended for goods en route to events like tradeshows, where they would be used for demonstration rather than for sale. The \"ATA\" indicates that the goods are not imports but will be admitted only temporarily.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following Incoterms indicates that the exporter has the most responsibility for transporting a shipment of cargo from the exporter's dock to the importer's dock?","choices":["A. FOB ","  B. EXW ","  C. DDP ","  D. CIP "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"While it's not necessary to memorize the meanings of Incoterms, the important point to recall is that they exist to clarify the responsibilities of exporter and importer in a carriage contract. Of the four groups of terms, the E group (comprising only the single term EXW) puts the most responsibility on the importer, while the D group assigns almost all responsibility to the exporter. DDP, for example, means \"Delivered Duty Paid\" (that is, paid by the exporter).  "},{"question":"In a multiple-echelon distribution network where each warehouse orders independently based on local demand, where in the chain do you find the most variance in order quantity?","choices":["A. Variability tends to remain constant along the chain. ","  B. Variability tends to increase toward the customer end of the chain. ","  C. Variability tend to be greatest in the middle of the chain, diminishing toward either end. ","  D. Variability tends to increase toward the raw materials end of the chain. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"In many chains, variance in order quantity tends to increase as you move upstream away from the end customer. This is the bullwhip effect.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following actions is most likely to mitigate the negative consequences of the bullwhip effect?","choices":["A. Rationing ","  B. Cross-docking to reduce inventory storage time ","  C. Increasing sales and special offers ","  D. Multiple demand forecasts along the chain "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Reducing storage time by cross-docking can reduce delivery lead times, thus removing one of the factors that lead to forecast error and excess safety stock. The other options listed are likely to increase variability rather than reduce it.  "},{"question":"Which of the following approaches to product design is compatible with the requirement that German brewers use refillable bottles?","choices":["A. Design for reverse logistics ","  B. Over-the-wall design ","  C. Design for production ","  D. Design for logistics"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Design for reverse logistics looks for ways to make products that can be easily reused, returned, or recycled. (Whether the beer bottles can be reused or not has no effect upon logistics in the forward chain, only in the reverse chain that brings the product back at the end of its life cycle.)  "},{"question":"The marketing department's involvement with product management includes which of the following phases of the product's life cycle?","choices":["A. Development through introduction ","  B. Introduction only ","  C. Conception through maturity ","  D. All phases, from conception through withdrawal "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Marketing can play a useful role in planning, tracking, and managing demand from the beginning to the end of the life cycle.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following processes results in production numbers driven by dependent demand?","choices":["A. Master production scheduling process ","  B. Sales and operations planning process ","  C. Material requirements planning process ","  D. Market planning process"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The MRP schedules delivery of dependent demand items (which are in turn based upon independent demand forecasts). The other processes work with independent demand or product families.  "},{"question":"Which of the following correctly identifies the deseasonalized monthly demand (to the nearest whole number) for the first half of the calendar year in the example shown in the table below? ","choices":["A. 100 ","  B. 105 ","  C. 186 ","  D. 630 "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The deseasonalized demand is the sum of the seasonal averages divided by the number of \"seasons\" (or months) listed: (100 + 102 + 105 + 106 + 107 + 110) / 6 = 630 / 6 = 105.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following benefits has been realized under the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA)?","choices":["A. Elimination of barriers to transportation across the U.S.-Mexican border ","  B. Elimination of many regional tariffs ","  C. Easier access to competitively priced goods from outside the region ","  D. Simplified documentation to qualify for lower tariffs on regional goods "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"NAFTA eliminated many tariffs on imports originating from within the region and scheduled elimination of the rest. Other barriers, such as access to roads on either side of the U.S.-Mexican border, remain troublesome. Imports originating from countries within the region are granted favorable duties compared to goods from outside, but documenting country of origin can be troublesome. "},{"question":"Which of the following documents would a banker consult for information about the value of export-import cargo in connection with a letter of credit?","choices":["A. Commercial invoice ","  B. Dock receipt ","  C. Ship's manifest ","  D. Order bill of lading "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The commercial invoice is the document that states the value of commodities in a shipment. (It does not include other amounts, such as freight.)  "},{"question":"Which of the following firms generally acts as a shipper's long-term consulting partner, smoothing the way through foreign customs and politics but not buying or selling cargo?","choices":["A. Export management company ","  B. Freight forwarder ","  C. Export trading company ","  D. Customs house broker "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"An export management company (EMC) may actually engage in trade but generally as a long-term consultant to a shipper. The shipper benefits from the EMC's special knowledge of a foreign country's regulations, customs, and politics.  "},{"question":"In general, the largest portion of a product's delivery cost can be attributed to which of the following?","choices":["A. Handling ","  B. Production/assembly ","  C. Product design ","  D. Transportation"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"As much as 70 percent of a product's delivery cost is attributable to its design.  "},{"question":"If you know the available time at a work center and want to calculate its rated capacity, you also need to know which of the following?","choices":["A. Utilization and number of workers/machines ","  B. Efficiency and number of workers/machines ","  C. Efficiency and manufacturing lead time ","  D. Efficiency and utilization "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"To calculate rated capacity, you multiply the number of available hours by the efficiency and utilization. Essentially, that tells you how much of the available time is being used and how efficiently it's being used.  "},{"question":"Which of the following often accompanies goods that are intended to travel in sealed containers across borders, including goods intended only to be admitted temporarily for use in events such as tradeshows?","choices":["A. ATA Carnet ","  B. Order waybill ","  C. Bill of lading ","  D. Consular invoice "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The Carnet, or ATA Carnet, was originally intended for goods en route to events like tradeshows, where they would be used for demonstration rather than for sale. The \"ATA\" indicates that the goods are not imports but will be admitted only temporarily.  "},{"question":"Which of the following types of carriers is required to serve the public, practice nondiscrimination, charge reasonable rates, and assume many of the risks of transport?","choices":["A. Contract carrier ","  B. Private carrier ","  C. Common carrier ","  D. All of the above"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Common carriers are subject to the most regulation, including the requirement to serve all customers within the scope of their license, practice nondiscrimination, and charge rates that are neither too high nor too low as to distort the market (reasonable rates). They also bear considerable responsibility for protecting the cargo that they carry.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is an input to rough-cut capacity planning (RCCP)?","choices":["A. Aggregate output per product family ","  B. Master schedule ","  C. Weekly output per component ","  D. Weekly output per end item "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"RCCP determines if resources are available (or can be made available) in the network to achieve the goals in the master schedule.  "},{"question":"Inventory held to cover transit time is called which of the following?","choices":["A. Work-in-process inventory ","  B. Pipeline inventory ","  C. Fluctuation inventory ","  D. Anticipatory inventory "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Pipeline inventory is stock kept on hand to fill orders while the next lot is in transit. It is also known as transportation inventory.  "},{"question":"Which of the following may increase as a tradeoff when a logistics chain institutes risk pooling by moving inventory from several smaller warehouses to a larger central storage facility?","choices":["A. Inventory handling costs ","  B. Delivery lead times ","  C. Number of stockouts ","  D. Total amount of inventory held at one time"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Risk pooling is a means of reducing the risk of stockouts by consolidating inventory in a central warehouse. With a larger store of goods in the central warehouse, even the largest, unexpected order will have less chance of exhausting the inventory, as it might in a smaller warehouse. With fewer facilities adding safety stock to their orders (plus the lower stockout risk), the total amount of inventory can be reduced, and less inventory means lower holding and handling expenses. Lead times may go up, however, for deliveries made to customers that are more distant from the central warehouse than from the smaller facilities it replaced.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following is not allowed in a foreign trade zone?","choices":["A. Repackaging or otherwise altering cargo to remedy potential customs violations ","  B. Storing goods tax-free for an indefinite period of time ","  C. Performing break-bulk operations to reduce import duties owed ","  D. Retail trade  "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Retail trade is forbidden inside a foreign trade zone. All the other activities are specifically permitted.  "},{"question":"Lead time can be determined from the information in which of the following?","choices":["A. Work center file ","  B. Routing file ","  C. Open order file ","  D. Both a and b "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The routing and work center files contain all the times necessary to calculate the total lead time.  "},{"question":"Which of the following correctly identifies the cost structure of trucking?","choices":["A. Low fixed costs, low variable costs ","  B. High fixed costs, low variable costs ","  C. Low fixed costs, high variable costs ","  D. High fixed costs, high variable costs "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The public builds and maintains the infrastructure used by trucks, so they have low fixed costs. But they have relatively high variable costs for operation and maintenance.  "},{"question":"Which of the following forecast methods predicts demand for one product by looking at data from a different product?","choices":["A. Personal insight ","  B. Historical analogy ","  C. Visionary method ","  D. Market research "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Historical analogy forecasts use demand data from one product to forecast demand for a different but similar product, such as a new product for which no past data exist.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following represents a sound approach to tracking data to use in demand forecasting?","choices":["A. Exclude cancellations and returns. ","  B. Exclude consideration of competitors' activities. ","  C. Include data by ship date, not order date. ","  D. Include all product options. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Forecast data should include demand for all product options as well as total demand for the product. You want to know when items were in demand, not when they were shipped. Competitors' product introductions are likely to affect your forecasts. Returns and cancellations should be subtracted from orders when calculating actual demand.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following entities is responsible for issuing and updating Incoterms?","choices":["A. World Trade Organization ","  B. United Nations ","  C. International Chamber of Commerce (ICC) ","  D. U.S. Department of Commerce"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Incoterms were first issued in 1936 by the International Chamber of Commerce, which has updated them several times since then to reflect the changing conditions of international trade.  "},{"question":"Referring to the demand table below, calculate forecasts for May using both the three-month moving average (MA) and the naive forecasting methods. Which of the following statements correctly identifies the two forecasts? ","choices":["A. MA forecast = 20.33; naive forecast = 22 ","  B. MA forecast = 20.67; naive forecast = 20 ","  C. MA forecast = 21.33; naive forecast = 22 ","  D. MA forecast = 22.00; naive forecast = 17"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The three-month moving average forecast for May is 20.33, which is the average monthly demand for the months from February through April (17 + 22 + 22 = 61 / 3 = 20.33); the naive forecast is taken from the period preceding the forecast period, which in this case is 22, the actual demand for May. Note that the naive forecast (22) is more nearly accurate in this case, because it adjusts faster than the moving average. However, it could just as easily have been less accurate if demand had changed in a different direction or by a different amount.  "},{"question":"Referring to the table below, calculate a seasonal forecast for the month of June (round to two decimal places). If the deseasonalized forecast for January to June in a future year is 115, which of the following correctly identifies the seasonalized forecast for June of that year? ","choices":["A. 121 ","  B. 115 ","  C. 110 ","  D. 109 "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The seasonal index is the seasonal average demand divided by the deseasonalized average. The seasonal index for June is 1.05. The June forecast in the upcoming year would be the deseasonalized average of 115 multiplied by the June seasonal index: 115 x 1.05 = 120.75 (rounds to 121).  "},{"question":"For which of the following items should demand be calculated rather than forecast?","choices":["A. All Chevrolets ","  B. All Chevrolet Cobalts ","  C. All steering wheels for new Chevrolet Cobalts ","  D. All Chevrolet replacement parts "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Steering wheels are a dependent demand item; the demand for dependent items should be calculated from the forecast of demand for their parent items. Steering wheels are a component; the new cars they go into are the parents. Replacement parts are sold, manufactured, and forecast as independent items, not as dependent components.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following types of warehousing is most appropriate for agricultural supplies that might be used only once during the year?","choices":["A. Postponement ","  B. Assortment ","  C. Stockpiling ","  D. Spot stocking"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Spot stocking is used for limited product lines and highly seasonal products that can be centrally stored during most of the year and spot-stocked in season at warehouses near the places where they will be purchased and used. Manufacturers use spot stocking for agricultural products used only during one limited operation, such as harvesting.  "},{"question":"If you were able to get a 20 percent discount on any of the following logistics expenses, which would you choose to receive the maximum cost savings?","choices":["A. Warehousing ","  B. Compliance ","  C. Materials handling ","  D. Transportation"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Transportation expenses make up the largest portion of the logistics budget, so taking the discount on transportation costs would give you the largest cost reduction. (Of course, you would have to consider possible tradeoffs if discounting transportation caused cost increases elsewhere in the system.)  "},{"question":"Using a pull system in the distribution network offers which one of the following benefits to the supply chain as a whole?","choices":["A. Enhanced visibility of future demand all along the chain ","  B. Elimination of safety stock ","  C. Sensitivity to demands of the final customer ","  D. Enhanced communication up the chain"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The main benefit of the pull system of distribution is sensitivity to local customer demand, since orders begin near the customer and \"pull\" products from upstream. This approach does not facilitate communication, eliminate safety stock, or improve visibility down the chain because there is no central coordination and upstream partners have to depend upon forecasting to plan for future orders rather than upon (for example) a predetermined production schedule.  "},{"question":"Which of the following smoothing constants would yield the same result as a naive forecast?","choices":["A. 0.01 ","  B. 0.05 ","  C. 0.50 ","  D. 1.0 "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Smoothing constants are generally chosen between 0.05 and 0.50. A constant of 0 would give the same forecast as for the previous month, because it would eliminate the portion of the equation including the forecast error. A constant of 1.0 would yield a forecast equal to the current month's demand; in the equation, the forecast numbers would cancel out, leaving only the actual demand amount. In between 0 and 1, the constant determines how much weight you give to the forecast error. "},{"question":"Which of the following modes of transporting petroleum involves the lowest operating costs?","choices":["A. Ocean vessel ","  B. Pipeline ","  C. Rail ","  D. Tanker truck "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Pipelines are costly in other ways, but their operating costs are relatively low (no drivers or pilots, for one thing).  "},{"question":"Which one of the following warehouse operations is most appropriate for a manufacturer that receives components from many suppliers and wants to achieve economies of scale when transporting those components to one plant?","choices":["A. Mixing ","  B. Cross-dock ","  C. Consolidation ","  D. Break-bulk"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"To achieve economies of scale in transportation, consolidation combines shipments from many incoming sources when loading outbound vehicles headed for a single location. "},{"question":"Which of the following is another name for the \"one size fits all\" type of design?","choices":["A. Standardization ","  B. Modular design ","  C. Component commonality ","  D. Mass customization"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Standardization, also called universality, is the strategy of designing a product to work in multiple markets rather than in only one market. Modular design and mass customization may reach multiple market segments, but they do so by product differentiation, not standardization.  "},{"question":"Which of the following has the highest fixed cost of any means of transporting petroleum?","choices":["A. Trains ","  B. Trucks ","  C. Ships ","  D. Pipelines"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Expenses related to construction, right of way, and pumping capacity give pipelines the highest fixed costs of any mode of transporting freight.  "},{"question":"In the CPFR model, which of the following tasks would be performed jointly by the manufacturer (seller) and the retailer (buyer)?","choices":["A. POS (point-of-sale) forecasting ","  B. Market data analysis ","  C. Sales forecasting ","  D. All of the above would be performed jointly.  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"In the model, certain tasks are performed by the buyer/retailer (POS forecasting in this case), certain tasks are performed by the seller/manufacturer (market analysis in this case), and those tasks are reconciled in a joint session. The joint session to reconcile POS forecasting and market analysis results in a shared sales forecast. "},{"question":"CPFR includes formal guidelines for a growing number of scenarios. Which of the following CPFR scenarios includes such methods as graphical presentations of new products to help make merchandizing decisions in the absence of solid historical data on demand?","choices":["A. Collaborative assortment planning ","  B. DC replenishment collaboration ","  C. Store replenishment collaboration ","  D. Retail event collaboration "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Assortment planning in industries in which demand and product styles change with each season present a special challenge to forecasters. The constant rotation through different styles or models means there is little historical demand data for particular products. VICS CPFR includes a scenario with guidelines for assortment planning based on graphic presentations of new models along with financial models.  "},{"question":"According to the World Trade Organization, which of the following is the right amount to use when declaring the value of imported goods?","choices":["A. Exporter's cost plus transaction expenses ","  B. Amount stated in the harmonized code for the goods in the cargo ","  C. Actual price to the importer ","  D. Calculated market value "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The price paid (or scheduled to be paid) by the importer is the right amount to use when declaring the value of an import. The WTO does permit other \"reasonable\" methods of valuation if circumstances warrant. "},{"question":"Which one of the following is a negotiable certificate of ownership?","choices":["A. Straight B/L ","  B. Air waybill ","  C. Order B/L ","  D. Dock receipt"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Order B/Ls can be used to transfer ownership of cargo. Straight B/Ls (including air bills) document cargo intended for delivery straight to the buyer without intermediate title transfers.  "},{"question":"Which of the following identifies a risk of ordering more inventory than required to fill forecast orders?","choices":["A. Increased obsolescence ","  B. Higher per-car costs for transporting the inventory ","  C. Decoupling from supplier ","  D. Higher per-item costs for purchasing the inventory"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The risk of having inventory items become obsolete increases when amounts ordered exceed the forecast significantly. Economies of scale in transport and purchase are potential benefits of larger orders, as is decoupling from the supplier.  "},{"question":"How frequently does a firm update S\u0026OP data?","choices":["A. Continuously ","  B. Daily ","  C. Monthly ","  D. Quarterly "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Data are updated as quickly as possible after the end of the month as part of the regular S\u0026OP process.  "},{"question":"A logistics manager concerned to avoid breakage of cargo would be least inclined to choose which of the following modes of transportation (ignoring tradeoffs)?","choices":["A. Water transport ","  B. Rail transport ","  C. Truck transport ","  D. Air transport "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Rail provides a rough ride for cargo, resulting in more breakage than occurs in cargo transported by truck, water, or air.  "},{"question":"Which of the following parties determines the tariff classification of an import?","choices":["A. Exporter ","  B. World Trade Organization inspectors ","  C. Importer ","  D. Customs "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The exporter bears responsibility for determining the classification of the goods it sells in international transactions. It does so by reference to the harmonized tariff codes.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following benefits has been realized under the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA)?","choices":["A. Easier access to competitively priced goods from outside the region ","  B. Elimination of many regional tariffs ","  C. Elimination of barriers to transportation across the U.S.-Mexican border ","  D. Simplified documentation to qualify for lower tariffs on regional goods "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"NAFTA eliminated many tariffs on imports originating from within the region and scheduled elimination of the rest. Other barriers, such as access to roads on either side of the U.S.-Mexican border, remain troublesome. Imports originating from countries within the region are granted favorable duties compared to goods from outside, but documenting country of origin can be troublesome.  "},{"question":"The forecasting method known as the pyramid technique specifically incorporates which one of the following principles of forecasting?","choices":["A. Forecasts are always wrong. ","  B. Short-range forecasts are more reliable than long-range forecasts. ","  C. Product group forecasts are more reliable than single-product forecasts. ","  D. Quantitative data are preferable to qualitative estimates."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Product group forecasts are more reliable than single-product forecasts, so the pyramid technique begins by forecasting demand for the product family and then disaggregates the demand to generate single-product demand forecasts. This ensures alignment between forecasts for the group and the components of the group. (This is not to imply that the technique ignores other principles, only that it specifically relies upon the superior reliability of group forecasting.)  "},{"question":"The exporter takes the most risk in which of the following export-import financing arrangements?","choices":["A. Letter of credit ","  B. Consignment of goods ","  C. Buyer's payment from an open account ","  D. Seller's credit"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"In seller's credit financing, the seller (exporter) accepts the importer's credit card (or other promise to pay) and thus takes the most financial risk involved in any of options described.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following would a firm be most likely to choose to deliver goods in national markets if it is looking for tailored services and a relatively low negotiated rate?","choices":["A. Private carrier ","  B. Exempt carrier ","  C. Contract carrier ","  D. Common carrier "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Contract carriers can generally offer lower rates and tailored services to select clients.  "},{"question":"Which of the following correctly describes the benefit of conducting periodic inventory counts?","choices":["A. Periodic counts don't disrupt the ordinary flow of business. ","  B. Periodic counting promotes accurate ordering. ","  C. Periodic counting is inexpensive. ","  D. Periodic counting provides a financial value for all inventory at one point in time. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Periodic inventory counts provide a value for inventory at one point in time, but they disrupt business, are relatively expensive, are prone to inaccuracy, and don't promote accurate ordering policies (because they are infrequent and tend to be inaccurate).  "},{"question":"Which of the following features was a drawback in the early versions of MRP software?","choices":["A. Assumed infinite capacity ","  B. Lacked an automated bill of materials ","  C. Failed to include component lead times ","  D. Made extra work for the scheduler "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The earliest versions of MRP software assumed infinite capacity and therefore would sometimes create impossible schedules.  "},{"question":"The sales and operations plan would include which of the following?","choices":["A. Monthly production figures by individual manufacturing center ","  B. Weekly production figures by individual SKU ","  C. Monthly production figures by product family ","  D. Monthly production figures for individual SKUs "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"S\u0026OP focuses on monthly production amounts for product families. Scheduling for individual products (SKUs) comes later in the planning process.  "},{"question":"In the economic order quantity calculation, which one of the following statements most accurately identifies the effect of increasing order sizes on inventory holding and order costs?","choices":["A. Economies of scale lower all holding and ordering/setup costs equally and steadily. ","  B. Setup and order costs remain constant while holding costs drop steadily. ","  C. Holding costs remain constant while setup costs rise steadily. ","  D. Total costs drop up to a point and then rise steadily. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The larger the order, the higher the holding costs, because there is more inventory to hold. Setup costs tend to go down as orders grow larger because of economies of scale. (Larger orders can be placed less frequently than smaller orders, thus reducing the number of setups.)  "},{"question":"Which of the following would be a typical time horizon for sales and operations planning?","choices":["A. One week to one month ","  B. One month to one quarter ","  C. 12 to 18 months ","  D. 18 months to three years "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The sales and operations plan typically extends out at least a year and no more than 18 months and involves both short- and medium-term planning.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following statements identifies a beneficial result of including more periods in a moving average?","choices":["A. The impact of random variations is reduced. ","  B. Forecasts don't lag so far behind sales data. ","  C. Forecasts are more sensitive to trends in demand. ","  D. Forecasting becomes more sensitive to cyclical changes. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Including more periods in the calculation (six or 12 months instead of three, for example) further reduces the effects of random variation. This is the only benefit. Otherwise, the data gathering and calculations become more difficult and the forecasts lag farther behind changes in demand, making the forecasts less sensitive to trends and cycles. "},{"question":"Which of the following design strategies is the polar opposite of integral design?","choices":["A. Modular design ","  B. Design for postponement ","  C. Universality ","  D. Mass customization"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Modular design creates mix-and-match components that can be combined into different products, whereas integral design creates one product from a unique set of components.  "},{"question":"Considering the types of cargo typically carried over long distances by inland water carrier and the rates per ton-mile, which of the following modes of transportation is the barge's closest competitor?","choices":["A. Piggyback ","  B. Trucking ","  C. Rail ","  D. Pipeline"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Railroad and barges both specialize in carrying very heavy, dense, low-value cargo over long distances. A rail line laid along a waterway would make a potent rival for the water carrier.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following describes the typical situation in regards to payment of import duties?","choices":["A. The importer determines the tariff classification and the exporter pays the duty. ","  B. The exporter determines the tariff classification and pays the duty. ","  C. The importer determines the tariff classification and pays the duty. ","  D. The exporter determines the tariff classification and the importer pays the duty."],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The exporter determines the tariff classification using the harmonized code when packaging the goods for export. The importer (usually through the customs house broker) pays the duty when goods come through customs.  "},{"question":"Which of the following design strategies offers streamlined production and lower purchasing costs with a possible tradeoff against reduced design flexibility and lower quality?","choices":["A. Mass customization ","  B. Universality ","  C. Component commonality ","  D. Integral design"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Using common components for a variety of purposes provides economies of scale in purchasing and manufacture but can limit design flexibility and reduce quality.  "},{"question":"A demand forecast determined by a panel of all the salespeople in an organization may reach an exaggerated, false conclusion by relying on which of the following?","choices":["A. Intuition ","  B. Personal experience ","  C. Bandwagon effect ","  D. Collective view of their markets"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The \"bandwagon effect\" (also called \"groupthink\") can distort the conclusions of a panel if a strong leader emerges with a convincing but wrong-headed view, or if all participants reinforce one another in reaching an exaggerated conclusion. An entire sales force acting in concert may, however, benefit from experience, collective knowledge of the broad market served by the organization, and even intuition.  "},{"question":"A business plan would typically include which of the following?","choices":["A. Long-term guidance for developing tactical production plans ","  B. Clearly defined marketing tactics ","  C. Definition of sales territories ","  D. Monthly production figures for each product family "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The business plan provides a long-range view of strategy and guidance for developing tactical plans for sales, marketing, and operations.  "},{"question":"When an export-import transaction is financed by a letter of credit, which one of the following entities actually issues the letter?","choices":["A. Importer's bank ","  B. Ocean or air carrier ","  C. Buyer ","  D. Seller's bank"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The issuer of a letter of credit is the buyer/importer's bank, which attests in the letter to its faith that the importer can and will pay for the goods when certain conditions have been satisfied "},{"question":"Which of the following is an input to the material requirements plan (MRP)?","choices":["A. Input/output control ","  B. Resource requirements planning ","  C. Make/buy action plan ","  D. Rough-cut capacity planning"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Make/buy action plans concern matters such as what to order, cancel, and expedite. With the information from this and other sources, it is possible to develop the MRP.   "},{"question":"Which one of the following statements correctly identifies a consequence of the Staggers Act of 1980, which deregulated rail transport in the United States?","choices":["A. No significant change in share of commercial carriage (ton-mile/year) ","  B. Steady increase in miles of track in service ","  C. Steady increase in rates ","  D. Steady increase in markets served by rail "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Railroads have maintained a fairly steady 40 percent share of the market among common carriers since the Staggers Act, but other results of deregulation include declines in the number of large rail carriers, in total miles of track, in rates, and in destinations served.  "},{"question":"Using the bill of materials to deduct component quantities from inventory as soon as a unit has been manufactured is called which of the following?","choices":["A. Backflushing ","  B. Pegging ","  C. Bucket reduction ","  D. Offsetting "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Backflushing is the use of the bill of materials to eliminate a component from inventory as soon as the parent unit has been manufactured. Backflushing is used in connection with JIT, and it does assume the reduction or elimination of time buckets in scheduling.  "},{"question":"Which of the following could appear in a planning bill of materials?","choices":["A. All the parts necessary to manufacture one car radio ","  B. All the parts required to produce a component for use in mass customization ","  C. All the #10 nails intended for delivery to a chain of home improvement stores ","  D. All the transistors to be used in assembling a variety of electronics components "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"A planning bill of materials includes small items intended for use in a variety of finished items. They are ordered in bulk for convenience and economies of scale even though they have no one parent to list on a regular bill of materials.  "},{"question":"Place the following modes of transportation in order of rate per ton-mile for carrying cargo, with I being the lowest rates and IV being the highest.","choices":["I. ","\tRail ","\tII. ","\tAir "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Water transport offers the lowest rates per ton, much lower even than rail, which is second. Trucking is considerably more expensive than rail but substantially less expensive than air.  "},{"question":"A logistics manager might approach which one of the following intermediaries to purchase cargo space that the firm purchased elsewhere and marked up for resale?","choices":["A. Export trading company (ETC) ","  B. Freight forwarder ","  C. Consolidator ","  D. Non-vessel operating common carrier (NVOCC) "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"An NVOCC (non-vessel operating common carrier) buys cargo space on a carrier to resell to shippers. "},{"question":"Which of the following conditions is generally associated with lot-for-lot order sizing?","choices":["A. Large batches ","  B. Safety stock buffers ","  C. Small, frequent orders ","  D. Independent demand items "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Lot-for-lot sizing is typically used with small, frequent deliveries of dependent demand items. Longer time buckets and larger order sizes are more likely to require a buffer of safety stock.  "},{"question":"To be most effective, design of a reverse logistics chain should begin during which of the following phases of the product life cycle?","choices":["A. Product design ","  B. Introduction ","  C. Maturity ","  D. Decline"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Product design should take reverse logistics into account by considering use of resources, potential for reuse, recycling, etc.  "},{"question":"When deciding whether to acquire a component from a domestic or foreign source, which of the following comparisons provides the most accurate assessment of their relative value?","choices":["A. Simple price comparison ","  B. Relative price plus transportation ","  C. Relative price adjusted for currency exchange and import duties ","  D. Landed cost of each "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Landed cost includes every expense involved in acquiring a component (or any item of value) and bringing it to your dock, including price, transportation, fees and commissions, import duties, etc.  "},{"question":"Which of the following constitutes the primary reason for a supplier to agree to sell goods on consignment rather than selling to its customers for resale to the customer's customers?","choices":["A. Decreased setup costs ","  B. Decreased labor costs ","  C. Decreased inventory holding costs ","  D. Greater visibility of inventory management "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"In VMI, both partners benefit from increased visibility of the inventory management process, because they share information about retail demand on the one hand and supplier processes on the other. Setup and holding costs increase for the supplier, however, though they should decrease overall as forecasting improves.  "},{"question":"Which of the following types of warehouse ownership might a firm choose to minimize storage costs when adding distribution capacity for a new product with a highly seasonal demand pattern?","choices":["A. Public warehousing ","  B. Contract warehousing ","  C. Remodeled and expanded private warehousing ","  D. New construction private warehousing "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"All other factors being equal, public warehousing is a good choice to accommodate short-term spikes in demand. The other choices require longer-term commitments of resources. (In actual practice, \"other factors\" may be unlikely to remain equal, and all choices have to be made with an eye to unplanned consequences for the system as a whole.)  "},{"question":"Which of the following descriptions applies most accurately to quick response collaboration?","choices":["A. Basic type of collaboration that involves the sharing of point-of-sale (POS) information ","  B. Complex and evolving guidelines for coordinating multiple aspects of supply chain partnership ","  C. Partnership in which a supplier and a retailer collaborate on development of shipping schedules ","  D. Arrangement in which a supplier may handle some aspects of inventory management for a retailer "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Quick response (QR) is one of the earliest and most basic forms of customer-supplier partnerships, in which the retailer shares POS information with the supplier but doesn't collaborate on forecasting. "},{"question":"Which of the following would be subject to alteration as the result of decisions made in an executive S\u0026OP meeting?","choices":["A. Business plan ","  B. Product features ","  C. Product pricing ","  D. Weekly production schedules "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The monthly S\u0026OP meeting deals with aggregate-level information about product families and output. The S\u0026OP executive committee can make changes in either the operations plan or the business plan if they get out of synch with one another.  "},{"question":"Pick-to-light systems speed inventory retrieval when used in conjunction with which of the following material-handling equipment?","choices":["A. Automated storage and retrieval system (AS/RS) ","  B. Automatic sorting devices ","  C. Carousels ","  D. Automated conveyers "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Pick-to-light systems add lights to carousels to provide information such as the location and number of items to retrieve.  "},{"question":"Moving average forecasts are generally superior to naive forecasts in correcting for which of the following sources of variability?","choices":["A. Long-term trends ","  B. Very short-term fluctuations in demand attributable to no known cause ","  C. Cyclical movements correlated to economic indicators ","  D. Short- to medium-term trends related to the seasons of the year"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Moving averages are intended to even out random fluctuations, but they don't react quickly enough to changes to forecast cycles and trends.  "},{"question":"Referring to the demand table below, calculate a three-month weighted moving average forecast for April using a 3-2-1 weighting for March, February, and January, respectively. Which of the following identifies the correct forecast for April using this method? ","choices":["A. 20.17 ","  B. 20.33 ","  C. 20.67 ","  D. 40.33 "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The three-month weighted moving average forecast for April is 20.17 (3 x 22 = 66; 2 x 17 = 34; 1 x 21 = 21; 66 + 34 + 21 = 121; 121 / 6 = 20.17). Did you remember to divide by the sum of the weights (6) instead of by 3?  "},{"question":"If you favored a push approach to managing a supply chain, which of the following production strategies would you be most likely to adopt?","choices":["A. JIT ","  B. Make-to-order ","  C. Make-to-stock ","  D. Assemble-to-order"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A make-to-stock strategy \"pushes\" materials and products through the system in accordance with preset schedules rather than letting them be \"pulled\" through by actual orders.  "},{"question":"When international trade is financed with a letter of credit, which of the following entities actually makes the final payment to the seller?","choices":["A. Buyer ","  B. Inland export carrier ","  C. Buyer's bank ","  D. Seller's bank "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The seller (exporter) sends a draft to its banker, who honors it based upon its assurance of reimbursement by the buyer's bank, which in its turn depends upon reimbursement by the buyer (whose money it may already hold on account).  "},{"question":"Which of the following is generally considered to be the most responsible strategy for managing reverse logistics?","choices":["A. Breaking down returned goods to reuse undamaged components ","  B. Accepting product returns for recycling by the manufacturer ","  C. Reduction of resources used in extraction, manufacture, and packaging ","  D. Accepting product returns for efficient delivery to a clean landfill "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Reducing use of resources ranks highest in the reverse logistics hierarchy. The other strategies mentioned are also responsible and should be used when options higher up the pyramid are not feasible.  "},{"question":"Which of the following production strategies is sometimes called mass customization?","choices":["A. Make-to-stock ","  B. Make-to-order ","  C. Assemble-to-order ","  D. Lean production"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The assemble-to-order strategy incorporates some of the benefits of mass production and some of the benefits of true customization by mass-producing components that can be assembled into one of several different versions of a product after receipt of an order.  "},{"question":"A hard drive that can be used in many different kinds of computers is an example of which of the following design strategies?","choices":["A. Modular design ","  B. Standardization ","  C. Integral design ","  D. Universality"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A hard drive is a module that, along with other modules, can be mixed and matched to assemble computers with many different features.  "},{"question":"Which of the following documents constitutes a price quote in export-import trade?","choices":["A. Dock receipt ","  B. Pro forma commercial invoice ","  C. Consular invoice ","  D. Commercial invoice "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"A pro forma commercial invoice, constituting a price quote, may be filled out and sent before a deal has been struck between an exporter and a potential buyer. The buyer (importer) can use the pro forma commercial invoice when securing a letter of credit with its banker.  "},{"question":"If you know the available time at a work center and want to calculate its rated capacity, you also need to know which of the following?","choices":["A. Efficiency and number of workers/machines ","  B. Efficiency and utilization ","  C. Utilization and number of workers/machines ","  D. Efficiency and manufacturing lead time"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"To calculate rated capacity, you multiply the number of available hours by the efficiency and utilization. Essentially, that tells you how much of the available time is being used and how efficiently it's being used. "},{"question":"Which of the following (assuming site- and period-specific data) would provide the number of operations that can be produced at a site during a single period of time?","choices":["A. Total time available divided by load ","  B. Lead time available divided by total time ","  C. Lead time available divided by load ","  D. Total time available divided by lead time"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Dividing the total time available during a scheduled period at the site by the lead time tells you how many operations can be produced at the site in the period.  "},{"question":"For make-to-stock production of an integral design, the master production schedule includes production dates for which of the following?","choices":["A. Product families ","  B. Components ","  C. End items ","  D. Orders"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The master production schedule includes dates of production for make-to-stock end items. (This can be either finished products or, in a modular approach, components.)  "},{"question":"Which of the following collaborations has increasingly evolved from the traditional relationship of supplier as seller and retailer as buyer into a consignment-sales arrangement in which the supplier owns the goods until the end customer buys them?","choices":["A. Quick replenishment ","  B. Rapid replenishment ","  C. Vendor-managed inventory (VMI) ","  D. Continuous replenishment "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"VMI, a more sophisticated partnership than CR (also known as RR) and QR, has increasingly tended to involve consignment sales.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following is the most compelling reason for a manufacturer to own its own warehouses rather than using a contractor's warehouses?","choices":["A. To increase flexibility to test new geographic markets ","  B. To increase control over warehouse design decisions ","  C. To increase flexibility of budgeting for warehousing expenses ","  D. To benefit from economies of scale in transportation "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"A firm can build or remodel its own warehouses with no needs in mind other than its own. Contractors offer flexibility and economies of scale.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following is the most significant drawback of specialized package carriers such as FedEx and DHL?","choices":["A. Price ","  B. Lack of flexibility in pickup and delivery locations ","  C. Too expensive for small businesses to use economically ","  D. Lack of multimodal capability "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"With their intermodal networks, FedEx, UPS, and DHL offer door-to-door delivery on rapid timetables, but they are not inexpensive. As delivery services, they are perhaps best used when speed is more important than price. Many express services offer logistics consultation and total logistics management (4PL) and are capable of providing small businesses the benefit of economies of scale and deep logistics expertise.  "},{"question":"Which of the following approaches to product design is compatible with the requirement that German brewers use refillable bottles?","choices":["A. Design for logistics ","  B. Over-the-wall design ","  C. Design for production ","  D. Design for reverse logistics"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Design for reverse logistics looks for ways to make products that can be easily reused, returned, or recycled. (Whether the beer bottles can be reused or not has no effect upon logistics in the forward chain, only in the reverse chain that brings the product back at the end of its life cycle.)  "},{"question":"In regard to technology, CPFR may be said to depend fundamentally upon which of the following?","choices":["A. Peer-to-peer network ","  B. Third-party host ","  C. Shared data in any technological format ","  D. World Wide Web"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Although CPFR is enhanced by software, it is fundamentally a set of business practices for synchronizing the operations of buyer and seller. It depends for success upon a willingness to share data for forecasting, execution, assessments, and other functions. The data may be shared on peer-to-peer networks, extranets, or third-party servers, and the Internet is generally involved as the medium for accessing the shared data. But technology is not at the heart of the matter; sharing data in joint operations is.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following describes the main drawback of the crane truck?","choices":["A. High operator costs ","  B. Lack of flexibility compared to forklifts ","  C. High fixed cost ","  D. Requirement of wide aisles for maneuverability"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Crane trucks (or stacker cranes) are capital-intensive purchases, but they are available in driverless models to eliminate operator costs. They offer similar flexibility to forklifts and can move through narrow aisles.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following production strategies sometimes meets resistance from distribution centers because of the increased demands for skill training and capacity expansion?","choices":["A. Make-to-stock ","  B. Assemble-to-order ","  C. JIT ","  D. Make-to-order"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"An assemble-to-order strategy may require warehouse or sales personnel to complete the final stages of finishing a product, thus requiring workers to acquire new skills and, in some cases, the facility to expand capacity to accommodate the finishing operations.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following has constituted the greatest historical impediment to efficient use of railroads to carry freight in Europe?","choices":["A. Lack of uniform conditions in the various countries ","  B. Lack of government support ","  C. Increasing pressure for space on trains from commuters ","  D. High rates relative to other modes of carriage "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Trains are hindered in traveling across borders in Europe because of incompatible infrastructure and regulations. Rail freight carriage in Europe dropped steadily in the latter decades of the 20th century as other modes of freight carriage have increased in market share. At the same time, passenger use of trains also declined. Rail rates are relatively low, and rail transport has historically received strong government support in EU countries.  "},{"question":"Which of the following would contain information such as queue time and machine setup time?","choices":["A. Route sheet ","  B. Master production schedule ","  C. Component bill of materials ","  D. Order release form"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The route sheet lists the work centers a component passes through in temporal order along with the operations performed at each work center and the time spent in queues, etc.  "},{"question":"If you know the actual output of a work center and want to calculate its efficiency, you also need to know which of the following?","choices":["A. Utilization ","  B. Standard expected hours of output ","  C. Available time ","  D. Number of workers or machines"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The efficiency of a work center is the ratio of actual output to standard expected output; in other words, it's a measure of how well the work center is producing in relation to what it can reasonably be expected to produce.  "},{"question":"Which of the following strategies represents the traditional \"over the wall\" approach to product design?","choices":["A. Supplier plays no role in design. ","  B. Formal design team includes supplier. ","  C. Supplier informally makes recommendations to design engineers. ","  D. Supplier creates the design."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"In the traditional design process, the supplier plays no role in design. The design is created by design engineers and passed \"over the wall,\" figuratively, to manufacturing and other stakeholders.  "},{"question":"Flexible scheduling is most likely to be a priority for which of the following transportation stakeholders?","choices":["A. Carrier ","  B. Shipper ","  C. Consignee ","  D. Both shipper and consignee "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Shippers and consignees both want scheduling that suits their particular timing needs, whereas carriers tend to value stability. Hence the higher prices for services such as next-day air.  "},{"question":"Pegging refers to the ability to make a connection between the required numbers of a specific component and which of the following?","choices":["A. Demand forecast ","  B. Demand for the parent according to the MRP ","  C. Specific work center ","  D. Capacity plan "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Pegging is the ability to track dependent demand for a component back to demand for the parent by referring to the material requirements plan (MRP).  "},{"question":"Which of the following constitutes a major, direct input into a material requirements plan?","choices":["A. Rough-cut capacity planning ","  B. Marketing plan ","  C. Input/output tracking reports ","  D. Master production schedule"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The material requirements plan works off the master production schedule to ensure that all components are delivered on time to meet production schedules.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following actions is most likely to mitigate the negative consequences of the bullwhip effect?","choices":["A. Multiple demand forecasts along the chain ","  B. Increasing sales and special offers ","  C. Rationing ","  D. Cross-docking to reduce inventory storage time "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Reducing storage time by cross-docking can reduce delivery lead times, thus removing one of the factors that lead to forecast error and excess safety stock. The other options listed are likely to increase variability rather than reduce it.  "},{"question":"Which of the following constitutes the most appropriate shipment to send by truck?","choices":["A. Small, high-value items traveling a short distance ","  B. Bulky items traveling between cities ","  C. Heavy, low-value items traveling long distances ","  D. Small, high-value items traveling a long distance "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The strong suit of trucking is accessibility, since trucks can go to virtually any commercial location. This along with size and weight limits makes trucking most appropriate for carrying high-value items of smaller size for short hauls.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a standardized, nonnegotiable form listing items being shipped directly to the titleholder?","choices":["A. Ocean bill ","  B. Order B/L ","  C. Ship's manifest ","  D. Air waybill"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The air waybill is a nonnegotiable standardized form used by all air carriers.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following conditions is a potential drawback of lot-for-lot order sizing?","choices":["A. Inventory build-up ","  B. Incompatibility with JIT ","  C. High setup costs ","  D. High inventory costs "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Typically used with JIT, lot-for-lot sizing delivers the exact amount needed when it is needed, thereby eliminating inventory buffers. Frequent delivery of small lots requires more setups.  "},{"question":"Which of the following objectives was most important in traditional warehousing (before World War II)?","choices":["A. Minimizing inventory amounts ","  B. Full support throughout product life cycles ","  C. Rapid response ","  D. Market presence"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Marketing concerns drove the traditional warehousing strategy of placing a warehouse near each market and stocking it with sufficient inventory to ensure uninterrupted order fulfillment. Postwar growth of sophisticated logistics has added the other objectives.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is the primary focus of the master production schedule?","choices":["A. Weekly production amounts for individual products ","  B. Monthly aggregate production amounts for end items ","  C. Monthly aggregate production amounts for product families ","  D. Weekly aggregate production amounts for product families "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The focus of MPS is on weekly scheduling for individual products. You could derive the other amounts from the master schedule.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following conditions contributes to the supply chain phenomenon known as the bullwhip effect?","choices":["A. JIT production strategies ","  B. Inaccurate demand forecasting ","  C. Insufficient batch sizes ","  D. Shortened lead times "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"A major contributor to the bullwhip effect is inaccuracy in demand forecasting, which can lead to ordering too much or too little stock, thus contributing to the effect's exaggerated peaks and valleys of demand.  "},{"question":"Which of the following would provide a sound method for grouping products into product families for the operations plan?","choices":["A. Similarity of manufacturing processes ","  B. Similar seasonality ","  C. Appeal to a particular age group ","  D. National market destination "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Product families for purposes of the operations plan are best chosen by similar manufacturing requirements to facilitate other planning processes, such as production scheduling. (Marketing can group products in other ways for its purposes.) "},{"question":"In a multiple-echelon distribution network where each warehouse orders independently based on local demand, where in the chain do you find the most variance in order quantity?","choices":["A. Variability tends to increase toward the customer end of the chain. ","  B. Variability tends to increase toward the raw materials end of the chain. ","  C. Variability tend to be greatest in the middle of the chain, diminishing toward either end. ","  D. Variability tends to remain constant along the chain. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"In many chains, variance in order quantity tends to increase as you move upstream away from the end customer. This is the bullwhip effect.  "},{"question":"Piggyback service refers to which of the following types of cargo transport?","choices":["A. Combined truck and train transport ","  B. Combined train and ship transport ","  C. Combined plane and truck transport ","  D. Any intermodal method of transport"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"In piggyback service either a truck trailer or a container travels part of the way over the road and part of the way on a railroad flatcar. All the other intermodal methods mentioned in the options are available, and intermodal transport is an important option for the logistics manager to consider when navigating long logistics supply chains.  "},{"question":"By ordering extra stock (safety stock), a purchasing manager might reasonably expect to benefit the supply chain in all the following ways except","choices":["A. reducing overall supply chain costs. ","  B. reducing the likelihood of stockouts. ","  C. improving customer service. ","  D. anticipating unpredicted demand spikes."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Adding safety stock can achieve the goals of improved customer service, reduced stockouts, and anticipation of demand spikes; it is more likely to increase overall costs than reduce them. (Cost savings from reducing safety stock must, however, be balanced against the potential costs of increased stockouts.)  "},{"question":"Which of the following processes includes the disaggregation of product families?","choices":["A. Resource requirements planning ","  B. Operations planning ","  C. Master production scheduling ","  D. Sales planning"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Disaggregation takes place during the development of the master production schedule.  "},{"question":"Basing a demand forecast for kitchen appliances on housing start data is an example of which of the following?","choices":["A. Dependent demand forecasting ","  B. Extrinsic forecasting ","  C. Market analysis ","  D. Pyramid forecasting"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Basing a forecast for a product on data about economic indicators such as housing starts, population trends, or employment statistics is called extrinsic forecasting to distinguish it from intrinsic forecasting based on data about the product itself. Historical analogy bases forecasts for one product on data from a similar (analogous) product, not on data about economic trends.  "},{"question":"Which of the following institutions publishes the \"Orange Book\" containing recommendations that form the basis of international dangerous goods (hazardous materials) laws and regulations?","choices":["A. World Court ","  B. International Maritime Association ","  C. International Chamber of Commerce (ICC) ","  D. United Nations"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The \"Orange Book\" is published by the United Nations; its first edition came out in 1956. It contains the United Nations Recommendations on the Transport of Dangerous Goods (UNRMTDG), in which all national controls are grounded. The UN recommendations do not have the force of law, but national regulations based on them may.  "},{"question":"If you're planning to ship goods over the road, which of the following represents a strategy for lowering your per-pound costs for the trip?","choices":["A. Package the cargo to reduce load density. ","  B. Keep the weight down in each truck. ","  C. Ship to destinations with low lane volume. ","  D. Fill up the trucks."],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"A full truck qualifies for a per-pound (kilogram) discount, since the carrier benefits from being able to charge more per unit of weight. Similarly, heavier loads (subject to limits) and greater density yield economies of scale. \"Lane density\" refers to the amount of cargo traffic around the destination; greater density means more potential business for the carrier on the return trip. Low lane density can lead to a return trip with an empty vehicle, at the expense of the shipper.  "},{"question":"Which of the following design strategies would most likely be responsible for the fact that only one screwdriver is needed to remove all the screws securing a computer case and to unfasten all components from the motherboard inside?","choices":["A. Component commonality ","  B. Design for manufacture ","  C. Green engineering ","  D. Design for logistics "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Component commonality is the design strategy of substituting one common component for a variety of similar components.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements correctly identifies the major purpose of the sales and operations plan (S\u0026OP)?","choices":["A. S\u0026OP represents the first pass at balancing sales and output of end items. ","  B. S\u0026OP represents the mutual agreement of finance, sales, marketing, operations, and senior management on a single set of supply/demand numbers. ","  C. S\u0026OP represents the firm's essential planning document for use in securing startup financing from bankers and investors. ","  D. S\u0026OP represents the essence of a contract between sales and operations. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The sales and operations plan reconciles the business plans of all units of the firm, including finance, sales and marketing, and operations; the unified set of numbers has the approval of senior management. It is neither a contract between sales and operations nor a balance of end item supply and demand.  "},{"question":"Use of a fixed order quantity model is most likely to be effective in which of the following cases?","choices":["A. Demand is highly unpredictable and light. ","  B. Production is run on lean assumptions. ","  C. Lead time is highly variable. ","  D. Shipper is looking for quantity discounts"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Fixed quantity ordering is generally used to fill containers, qualify for quantity discounts, or both. The model works best when demand is known and stable with predictable lead times.  "},{"question":"In a letter of credit financing, which of the following documents must accompany a seller's draft to trigger payment?","choices":["A. Commercial invoice and certificate of origin ","  B. Commercial invoice and bill of lading ","  C. Dock receipt and bill of lading ","  D. Certificate of origin and dock receipt "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"A letter of credit typically requires that payment be contingent upon receipt of an invoice (which states the value of the cargo) and a bill of lading (which indicates that the cargo has been delivered to the carrier for transport). A description of the goods and their origin appears already in the L/C.  "},{"question":"According to the familiar Incoterm FOB, which one of the following entities holds title to export/import cargo once it has \"passed over the ship's rail\"?","choices":["A. Importer ","  B. Carrier ","  C. Exporter ","  D. Insurance company"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Once the cargo has \"passed over the ship's rail\" (to use the original terms), the importer takes title and is responsible for insurance, etc. The Incoterm stands for \"Free on Board\" (free, that is, from the exporter's point of view).  "},{"question":"Which of the following would not be an acceptable measurement of output for use in production planning?","choices":["A. Liters ","  B. Tons ","  C. Euros ","  D. Numbers "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The production plan focuses on the output of product (or services); pricing takes place elsewhere in the planning process.  "},{"question":"Which of the following changes tend to occur as a result of adding warehouses to a logistics network (assuming no other changes)?","choices":["A. Inventory increases and the ratio of storage space to total square feet increases. ","  B. Inventory decreases while the ratio of storage space to square feet increases. ","  C. Inventory decreases and the ratio of storage space to total square feet decreases. ","  D. Inventory increases while the ratio of storage space to total warehouse square feet decreases"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Increasing the number of warehouses tends to cause an increase in inventory as each adds a buffer of supply stock. On the other hand, the ratio of storage space to total square feet tends to decrease as each facility contains nonstorage areas that could be consolidated in a single warehouse.  "},{"question":"The impact of seasonality on demand in a fast-food restaurant might be measured in which of the following ways?","choices":["A. Time of year ","  B. Day of the week ","  C. Hour of the day ","  D. All of the above"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"As a demand planning concept, \"seasonality\" refers to demand patterns influenced by time, not just by the four seasons of the year. The restaurant business varies with the calendar, the day of the week, and the time of day.  "},{"question":"Which of the following correctly identifies the MAD for the six months in the example shown in the table below? ","choices":["A. -8.00 ","  B. 1.67 ","  C. 2.00 ","  D. 12.00"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The MAD (mean absolute deviation) is the average amount by which the forecast differs from the actual demand (Deviation = Demand - Forecast). It is \"absolute\" because it takes into account only the amount of the deviation, not the direction. Tracking the absolute deviation provides information for use in assessing the reliability of forecasts. "},{"question":"An importer will often give which one of the following independent operators power of attorney to pay import duties on its behalf?","choices":["A. ETC ","  B. Foreign carrier ","  C. Ship broker ","  D. Customs house broker"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The customs house broker specializes in moving imported goods through customs, expediting paperwork (which now takes place electronically), and paying the import duties under a power of attorney from the importer.  "},{"question":"Which of the following numbers is the correct seasonal average demand for February in the example shown in the table below (rounded to the nearest whole number)? ","choices":["A. 99 ","  B. 100 ","  C. 102 ","  D. 105 "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The seasonal average demand for February is the monthly average demand for the three Februarys listed: (101 + 101 + 105) / 3 = 102.  "},{"question":"Which of the following numbers gives the correct March forecast using the data below and the exponential smoothing approach? ","choices":["A. 10,100 ","  B. 10,110 ","  C. 10,120 ","  D. 10,150 "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The forecast is 10,100 if you use the exponential smoothing equation as follows: Forecast = Previous Forecast + α (Demand - Forecast), where α is the smoothing constant, or, in this instance, the forecast = 10,150 + .20 (9,900 - 10,150) = 10,100. (Demand for February is 9,900, or sales minus refunds.)  "},{"question":"Capacity control takes place against which of the following time horizons?","choices":["A. Everyday activity ","  B. Monthly horizon ","  C. Annual horizon ","  D. Long term"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Capacity control takes place in the very short term in the context of daily production.  "},{"question":"Which of the following items makes up the majority of rail cargo in the United States and Great Britain?","choices":["A. Heavy industrial products, such as automobiles and equipment ","  B. Forest products ","  C. Coal ","  D. Agricultural commodities"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Coal makes up the bulk of rail cargo in both the United States and Great Britain. Rail transport is most appropriate for heavy, durable items of low value like raw materials, agricultural products, chemicals, construction materials, and industrial metals.  "},{"question":"Which of the following design philosophies is most responsible for furniture that comes in kit form to be assembled by the retail customer at home?","choices":["A. Design for logistics ","  B. Design for manufacture ","  C. Design for the environment ","  D. Concurrent engineering"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Designing products in kit form makes them easier to transport, store, and package, all aspects of logistics.  "},{"question":"Which of the following offers the greatest security against loss of cargo when transporting petroleum?","choices":["A. Pipelines ","  B. Road ","  C. Water ","  D. Rail"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Pipelines are considered a very secure way to convey liquid cargo. Except for earthquakes or terrorist attacks, pipelines will carry appropriate freight with almost no risk of loss or damage.  "},{"question":"The EOQ ordering system will work adequately under which one of the following conditions?","choices":["A. Order intervals vary. ","  B. Seasonal demand varies. ","  C. Orders arrive in stages. ","  D. Lead times vary"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Using the economic order quantity effectively assumes a number of conditions, such as constant, known demand, constant lead times, and the simultaneous arrival of all items ordered. Order intervals may vary, but the quantity (EOQ) is fixed.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following types of third-party logistics firms schedules cargo transport but operates no carriers?","choices":["A. Export trading company (ETC) ","  B. Consolidator ","  C. Non-vessel operating common carrier (NVOCC) ","  D. Freight forwarder "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Freight forwarders function like \"travel agents for cargo,\" arranging for transport but not operating their own carriers.  "},{"question":"Capacity and materials are committed to specific orders inside which of the following zones on the master production schedule?","choices":["A. Frozen zone ","  B. Liquid zone ","  C. Slushy zone ","  D. Planning zone "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"When all capacity and materials have been committed to specific orders, a demand time fence may be placed on the MPS, marking off a frozen zone in which no orders can be filled without permission from senior management.  "},{"question":"Which of the following pieces of warehouse equipment provides maximum flexibility in the movement, placement, and retrieval of pallets?","choices":["A. Roller-type conveyer ","  B. Tow tractor with trailer ","  C. Forklift truck ","  D. Crane"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The forklift truck is designed specifically for moving, placing, and retrieving pallets. The other options either have less flexibility or are not especially suitable for moving small loads. "},{"question":"Which of the following might a logistics manager choose to carry raw materials in local markets at a relatively low rate determined by the market?","choices":["A. Private carrier ","  B. Contract carrier ","  C. Exempt carrier ","  D. Common carrier "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Exempt carriers are (as the name suggests) granted exemption from economic regulation if they carry certain types of products, including unprocessed agricultural products and raw materials. They generally operate locally and charge relatively low rates based on the going rates in their markets.  "},{"question":"From the inventory manager's point of view, pilferage contributes to which of the following costs?","choices":["A. Setup costs ","  B. Ordering costs ","  C. Logistics costs ","  D. Carrying costs "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Pilferage is considered to be one of the potential costs of carrying inventory.  "},{"question":"Of the following methods of treating obsolete goods, which is considered to be the least responsible?","choices":["A. Energy recovery ","  B. Incineration ","  C. Burial in a clean, responsible landfill ","  D. Disposal at a recycling center"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Among the least desirable methods of product disposal, delivery to a landfill scores dead last behind incineration, energy recovery, and recycling. However, some landfills are more responsible than others, and a landfill is a better place to deposit products at the end of their useful lives than rivers, lakes, and untended dumps.  "},{"question":"Referring to the table below, calculate a forecast for April using the three-month moving average method. Based on your calculation, which of the following statements correctly relates the forecast to the actual April demand of 22? ","choices":["A. Demand and forecast are the same. ","  B. Demand exceeds forecast by 1.  ","  C. Demand exceeds forecast by 2. ","  D. Demand exceeds forecast by 3. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The average demand for the three months from January through March is 20 (21 + 17 + 22 = 60; 60 / 3 = 20), so the forecast for April is 20, which is two less than the actual demand.  "},{"question":"When engaging the services of a fourth-party logistics provider, a logistics manager should be careful to minimize the effects of which of the following potential risks?","choices":["A. Reduction in flexible deployment of resources ","  B. Reduction in control ","  C. Less rapid adjustment to new customer technologies ","  D. Reduced economies of scale"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Transferring responsibility for logistics to a 4PL involves loss of control, so a manager may want to compensate with frequent reviews (at least at first). The upside of giving control of logistics to a specialist should be an increase in flexibility, greater economies of scale, and more advanced logistics technology. "},{"question":"Which one of the following warehouse operations resembles break-bulk, except that it combines products from more than one manufacturer and may also involve product storage?","choices":["A. Stockpiling ","  B. Cross-docking ","  C. Consolidation ","  D. Assembly "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Consolidation is the process of breaking down incoming shipments from a variety of sources to mix the various products together in combinations specified by a number of recipients. (The process is also called mixing.) The mix of products may include items from storage as well as those just received.  "},{"question":"According to the ABC system of classifying inventory, an application of the Pareto principle, the greatest share of revenue will be generated by which of the following numbers of inventory items (approximately)?","choices":["A. 80 percent ","  B. 55 percent ","  C. 30 percent ","  D. 15 percent "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The ABC system of classifying inventory asserts that the A items in your inventory will constitute only about 15 percent of the total number of items but will create 70 to 80 percent of value. This is an approximate application of the Pareto principle, or 80-20 rule, which holds that about 20 percent of possible causes account for about 80 percent of outcomes.  "},{"question":"Demand forecasts are likely to be most accurate for which of the following items?","choices":["A. All Dodge Stratus SE models ","  B. All Dodge Stratus models ","  C. All DaimlerChrysler cars ","  D. All Dodge Models"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The forecast accuracy is likely to be greatest for all DaimlerChrysler models (and then for all Dodges, all Dodge Stratuses, and all Dodge Stratus SEs, in descending order of accuracy). The larger the aggregate, the more accurate the forecast.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a type of supply chain collaboration formalized by the Voluntary Interindustry Commerce Standards Association (VICS)?","choices":["A. Collective planning, forecasting, and replenishment ","  B. Vendor-managed inventory ","  C. Continuous replenishment ","  D. Quick response"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Collaborative planning, forecasting, and replenishment (CPFR®) is a formal description of best practices developed and maintained by VICS to help supply chain partners develop successful collaborations.  "},{"question":"In the CPFR model, which of the following corresponds to the order-to-cash cycle?","choices":["A. Order fulfillment ","  B. Demand and supply management ","  C. Logistics/distribution ","  D. Execution"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The area of CPFR that corresponds to the order-to-cash cycle is execution, which includes the collaboration tasks of order generation and order fulfillment. Order fulfillment includes the enterprise task of logistics/distribution.  "},{"question":"When a logistics manager removes a complete echelon from the distribution chain to reduce overall expenses, there may be a tradeoff for expenses in which of the following areas?","choices":["A. Increased transportation costs for extra miles of carriage ","  B. Increased inventory holding costs ","  C. Increased taxes on property and equipment ","  D. Increased inventory handling costs "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Removing an echelon from the network should reduce all the costs specified in the options except for transportation costs. Removing one level of warehousing, for example, will most likely increase the number of miles goods are carried from the points upstream from the echelon to the points downstream. "},{"question":"Which one of the following firms, known in Japan as sogo shosha, may be a large conglomerate that actually buys goods in one country for sale in a foreign market?","choices":["A. Export trading company (ETC) ","  B. Foreign carrier ","  C. Consolidator ","  D. Ship broker "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"An ETC (export trading company) buys goods domestically to sell into foreign markets. Such firms are especially significant in Japan, where they may own steamship lines, warehouses, insurance services, and so forth.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following would appear in the route file?","choices":["A. Assembly instructions for a finished product ","  B. Work center ID ","  C. List of component items for one end item ","  D. Mechanical drawings of a finished product"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The route file identifies the work center where a particular process will take place.  "},{"question":"Which of the following identifies a type of collaboration in which a manufacturer of razor blades determines how its product is displayed on a retailer's shelves and performs cycle counting at the store?","choices":["A. Vendor-managed inventory (VMI) ","  B. Quick response (QR) ","  C. Continuous replenishment (CR) ","  D. Collaborative planning, forecasting, and replenishment"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"VMI (vendor-managed inventory) is a form of collaboration in which a supplier performs some or all of the inventory operations traditionally handled by a retailer, including display design, replenishment, inventory counting, record keeping, and so on. (VMI can overlap with other systems.)  "},{"question":"The master schedule shows inventory on hand of 150 items, scheduled production of 500 items, and booked orders of 400 items. Which of the following is the correct number of available-to-promise items?","choices":["A. 150 ","  B. 250 ","  C. 500 ","  D. 650"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Available-to-promise equals the inventory on hand plus scheduled production reduced by orders already on the books. The ATP continues to decline as orders come in during the period.  "},{"question":"Which of the following might participate on a team with design engineers in the process known as concurrent engineering?","choices":["A. Manufacturing engineers ","  B. Market researchers ","  C. Customer representatives ","  D. Any or all of the above"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Concurrent engineering (CE) is known by several other names, such as design for manufacture and participative design. Early instances in the 1980s focused on the importance of including manufacturing engineers in the design process to spot any design decisions that would make production more difficult and expensive. More stakeholders from suppliers, customers, and other functional areas may also participate.  "},{"question":"How often, under normal circumstances, does a pre-S\u0026OP meeting take place?","choices":["A. Weekly ","  B. Monthly ","  C. Quarterly ","  D. Annually "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Sales and operations planning (S\u0026OP) is a monthly process.  "},{"question":"Which of the following might cause cyclical movements in a time series of demand data?","choices":["A. Steady decline in buying related to the product cycle ","  B. Holiday shopping ","  C. Random changes in consumer sentiment ","  D. Recession "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The business cycle correlates with alternating medium-term advances and declines in consumer buying patterns. Cycles are not short-term fluctuations related to holidays or random events, nor are they steady trends in only one direction, such as might be caused by factors such as a product cycle or demographics. "},{"question":"Which of the following provides a point of reference for formulating the sales and operations plan?","choices":["A. Business plan ","  B. Marketing plan ","  C. Production forecast ","  D. Financial plan "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The sales and operations plan takes the business plan as its point of reference for developing a plan that balances supply and demand by merging input from sales and marketing on the one hand and operations on the other.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements best describes the relative care a warehouse manager should take in securing A, B, and C inventory items?","choices":["A. Provide best protection for A items. ","  B. Provide best protection for B items. ","  C. Provide best protection for C items. ","  D. Provide the same level of protection to all items"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"While protecting all items is obviously important, the most cost-effective approach may be to spend relatively more resources on A items than on the less valuable, but larger, percentage of inventory. "},{"question":"Which one of the following is most appropriate for lifting very heavy items while causing minimal disruption of floor activities in the area?","choices":["A. Stacker crane ","  B. Forklift truck ","  C. AGVS ","  D. Bridge crane "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Bridge cranes can lift very heavy objects and they operate from overhead, so they leave the floor free for other activities.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following would you select to move pallets through warehouse aisles while minimizing costs?","choices":["A. Tow tractors with trailers ","  B. Automated towlines ","  C. Forklift truck ","  D. Conveyer belt "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The conveyer belt has no operator, so it not only minimizes operator costs, it eliminates them. Automated towlines are not likely to appeal to the cost-conscious manager.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following functional areas is responsible for demand forecasting?","choices":["A. IT ","  B. Purchasing ","  C. Sales and marketing ","  D. Executive team "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The sales and marketing area is responsible and accountable for forecasting. Someone has to be responsible for the forecast for assessment purposes, but this does not mean that other areas cannot contribute to the forecast or that the forecast cannot be shared with other functional areas and supply chain partners. Information sharing is key to supply chain management.  "},{"question":"Which of the following forms the basis for a naive demand forecast?","choices":["A. Market analysis ","  B. Data from the last demand period ","  C. Analogy ","  D. Intuition"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Naive forecasting assumes that demand in the next period will equal demand in the last period. It is a form of quantitative forecasting but lacks any analysis.  "},{"question":"Which of the following forecast techniques relies upon an expert panel that responds to questionnaires and never meets face to face?","choices":["A. Sales force consensus forecasting ","  B. Delphi method ","  C. Pyramid forecasting ","  D. Historical analogy"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The Delphi method uses information from a panel of experts who respond anonymously to questionnaires. After several rounds of responses and critiques, a moderator produces a report expressing the collective opinion of the group.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements identifies the financial consequences to a U.S. firm under NAFTA when it transfers assembled materials from a maquiladora subcontractor back into the United States?","choices":["A. It pays no duty or tax. ","  B. It pays a duty but receives a duty drawback. ","  C. It pays a tax based on the value added in Mexico. ","  D. It pays use (sales) tax on the value of the finished goods. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Under NAFTA, U.S. firms that subcontract work to maqualidoras in Mexico pay only a tax based on the value added in Mexico, which is primarily attributable to low-wage labor.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following warehouse operations would take place at a manufacturer's centralized warehouse to facilitate delivery of one product to many retailers?","choices":["A. Consolidation ","  B. Spot stocking ","  C. Mixing ","  D. Break-bulk"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Break-bulk operations break an incoming shipment from one source into smaller lots for reshipping to specific customers.  "},{"question":"Which of the following constitutes a potentially appropriate way to segment a market?","choices":["A. Geography ","  B. Market potential ","  C. Age ","  D. Any of the above can be appropriate. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Market segmentation and the deployment of the sales force can be based upon any of a number of criteria, including but by no means limited to geography, market potential, or age.  "},{"question":"Which of the following transportation stakeholders is most likely to be in agreement with the government about the need for market regulation?","choices":["A. Shippers ","  B. The public ","  C. Carriers ","  D. Recipients "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"All market participants can benefit from well-crafted regulations regarding such matters as fairness and safety, but the public at large is most likely to be in synch with the government on the broad spectrum of regulations, from pricing through access to safety and environmental stewardship. (This assumes a government that is responsive to public demands.)  "},{"question":"The forecasting method known as the pyramid technique specifically incorporates which one of the following principles of forecasting?","choices":["A. Forecasts are always wrong. ","  B. Product group forecasts are more reliable than single-product forecasts. ","  C. Short-range forecasts are more reliable than long-range forecasts. ","  D. Quantitative data are preferable to qualitative estimates. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Product group forecasts are more reliable than single-product forecasts, so the pyramid technique begins by forecasting demand for the product family and then disaggregates the demand to generate single-product demand forecasts. This ensures alignment between forecasts for the group and the components of the group. (This is not to imply that the technique ignores other principles, only that it specifically relies upon the superior reliability of group forecasting.)  "},{"question":"Which of the following is another name for the \"one size fits all\" type of design?","choices":["A. Standardization ","  B. Mass customization ","  C. Modular design ","  D. Component commonality "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Standardization, also called universality, is the strategy of designing a product to work in multiple markets rather than in only one market. Modular design and mass customization may reach multiple market segments, but they do so by product differentiation, not standardization.  "},{"question":"When engaging the services of a fourth-party logistics provider, a logistics manager should be careful to minimize the effects of which of the following potential risks?","choices":["A. Reduction in control ","  B. Less rapid adjustment to new customer technologies ","  C. Reduction in flexible deployment of resources ","  D. Reduced economies of scale"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Transferring responsibility for logistics to a 4PL involves loss of control, so a manager may want to compensate with frequent reviews (at least at first). The upside of giving control of logistics to a specialist should be an increase in flexibility, greater economies of scale, and more advanced logistics technology. "},{"question":"CPFR includes formal guidelines for a growing number of scenarios. Which of the following CPFR scenarios includes such methods as graphical presentations of new products to help make merchandizing decisions in the absence of solid historical data on demand?","choices":["A. Retail event collaboration ","  B. Collaborative assortment planning ","  C. Store replenishment collaboration ","  D. DC replenishment collaboration"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Assortment planning in industries in which demand and product styles change with each season present a special challenge to forecasters. The constant rotation through different styles or models means there is little historical demand data for particular products. VICS CPFR includes a scenario with guidelines for assortment planning based on graphic presentations of new models along with financial models.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a type of supply chain collaboration formalized by the Voluntary Interindustry Commerce Standards Association (VICS)?","choices":["A. Vendor-managed inventory ","  B. Quick response ","  C. Collective planning, forecasting, and replenishment ","  D. Continuous replenishment"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Collaborative planning, forecasting, and replenishment (CPFR®) is a formal description of best practices developed and maintained by VICS to help supply chain partners develop successful collaborations.  "},{"question":"Which of the following pieces of warehouse equipment provides maximum flexibility in the movement, placement, and retrieval of pallets?","choices":["A. Roller-type conveyer ","  B. Forklift truck ","  C. Tow tractor with trailer ","  D. Crane "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The forklift truck is designed specifically for moving, placing, and retrieving pallets. The other options either have less flexibility or are not especially suitable for moving small loads.  "},{"question":"Which of the following would provide a sound method for grouping products into product families for the operations plan?","choices":["A. Appeal to a particular age group ","  B. Similar seasonality ","  C. Similarity of manufacturing processes ","  D. National market destination"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Product families for purposes of the operations plan are best chosen by similar manufacturing requirements to facilitate other planning processes, such as production scheduling. (Marketing can group products in other ways for its purposes.)  "},{"question":"Which of the following design strategies would most likely be responsible for the fact that only one screwdriver is needed to remove all the screws securing a computer case and to unfasten all components from the motherboard inside?","choices":["A. Design for manufacture ","  B. Design for logistics ","  C. Component commonality ","  D. Green engineering"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Component commonality is the design strategy of substituting one common component for a variety of similar components.  "},{"question":"In regard to technology, CPFR may be said to depend fundamentally upon which of the following?","choices":["A. Peer-to-peer network ","  B. Third-party host ","  C. Shared data in any technological format ","  D. World Wide Web "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Although CPFR is enhanced by software, it is fundamentally a set of business practices for synchronizing the operations of buyer and seller. It depends for success upon a willingness to share data for forecasting, execution, assessments, and other functions. The data may be shared on peer-to-peer networks, extranets, or third-party servers, and the Internet is generally involved as the medium for accessing the shared data. But technology is not at the heart of the matter; sharing data in joint operations is.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements best describes the relative care a warehouse manager should take in securing A, B, and C inventory items?","choices":["A. Provide best protection for A items. ","  B. Provide best protection for B items. ","  C. Provide best protection for C items. ","  D. Provide the same level of protection to all items. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"While protecting all items is obviously important, the most cost-effective approach may be to spend relatively more resources on A items than on the less valuable, but larger, percentage of inventory.  "},{"question":"Referring to the demand table below, calculate forecasts for May using both the three-month moving average (MA) and the naive forecasting methods. Which of the following statements correctly identifies the two forecasts? ","choices":["A. MA forecast = 20.33; naive forecast = 22 ","  B. MA forecast = 20.67; naive forecast = 20 ","  C. MA forecast = 21.33; naive forecast = 22 ","  D. MA forecast = 22.00; naive forecast = 17"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The three-month moving average forecast for May is 20.33, which is the average monthly demand for the months from February through April (17 + 22 + 22 = 61 / 3 = 20.33); the naive forecast is taken from the period preceding the forecast period, which in this case is 22, the actual demand for May. Note that the naive forecast (22) is more nearly accurate in this case, because it adjusts faster than the moving average. However, it could just as easily have been less accurate if demand had changed in a different direction or by a different amount.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following conditions is a potential drawback of lot-for-lot order sizing?","choices":["A. Inventory build-up ","  B. High setup costs ","  C. Incompatibility with JIT ","  D. High inventory costs "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Typically used with JIT, lot-for-lot sizing delivers the exact amount needed when it is needed, thereby eliminating inventory buffers. Frequent delivery of small lots requires more setups.  "},{"question":"If you favored a push approach to managing a supply chain, which of the following production strategies would you be most likely to adopt?","choices":["A. Make-to-order ","  B. Assemble-to-order ","  C. JIT ","  D. Make-to-stock"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"A make-to-stock strategy \"pushes\" materials and products through the system in accordance with preset schedules rather than letting them be \"pulled\" through by actual orders.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following statements correctly identifies a consequence of the Staggers Act of 1980, which deregulated rail transport in the United States?","choices":["A. No significant change in share of commercial carriage (ton-mile/year) ","  B. Steady increase in miles of track in service ","  C. Steady increase in markets served by rail ","  D. Steady increase in rates"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Railroads have maintained a fairly steady 40 percent share of the market among common carriers since the Staggers Act, but other results of deregulation include declines in the number of large rail carriers, in total miles of track, in rates, and in destinations served.  "},{"question":"From the inventory manager's point of view, pilferage contributes to which of the following costs?","choices":["A. Setup costs ","  B. Ordering costs ","  C. Carrying costs ","  D. Logistics costs "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Pilferage is considered to be one of the potential costs of carrying inventory.  "},{"question":"Which of the following statements correctly identifies the purpose of the weights in a weighted moving average?","choices":["A. To be more sensitive to recent trends in demand ","  B. To put more emphasis on long-term influences on demand ","  C. To take account of mean average deviation ","  D. To make data gathering and forecasting calculations simpler "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A weighted moving average puts more emphasis than a simple moving average does on the most recent demand numbers. Because of the weighting, it doesn't lag as far behind demand data as a simple moving average. Its focus, therefore, is on recent trends, not the long term. It isn't simpler.  "},{"question":"Which of the following institutions publishes the \"Orange Book\" containing recommendations that form the basis of international dangerous goods (hazardous materials) laws and regulations?","choices":["A. International Maritime Association ","  B. International Chamber of Commerce (ICC) ","  C. United Nations ","  D. World Court "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The \"Orange Book\" is published by the United Nations; its first edition came out in 1956. It contains the United Nations Recommendations on the Transport of Dangerous Goods (UNRMTDG), in which all national controls are grounded. The UN recommendations do not have the force of law, but national regulations based on them may.  "},{"question":"In the CPFR model, which of the following tasks would be performed jointly by the manufacturer (seller) and the retailer (buyer)?","choices":["A. POS (point-of-sale) forecasting ","  B. Market data analysis ","  C. Sales forecasting ","  D. All of the above would be performed jointly"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"In the model, certain tasks are performed by the buyer/retailer (POS forecasting in this case), certain tasks are performed by the seller/manufacturer (market analysis in this case), and those tasks are reconciled in a joint session. The joint session to reconcile POS forecasting and market analysis results in a shared sales forecast.  "},{"question":"If you were able to get a 20 percent discount on any of the following logistics expenses, which would you choose to receive the maximum cost savings?","choices":["A. Transportation ","  B. Compliance ","  C. Warehousing ","  D. Materials handling"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Transportation expenses make up the largest portion of the logistics budget, so taking the discount on transportation costs would give you the largest cost reduction. (Of course, you would have to consider possible tradeoffs if discounting transportation caused cost increases elsewhere in the system.) "},{"question":"Capacity control takes place against which of the following time horizons?","choices":["A. Everyday activity ","  B. Monthly horizon ","  C. Annual horizon ","  D. Long term"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Capacity control takes place in the very short term in the context of daily production.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following describes the typical situation in regards to payment of import duties?","choices":["A. The exporter determines the tariff classification and pays the duty. ","  B. The exporter determines the tariff classification and the importer pays the duty. ","  C. The importer determines the tariff classification and the exporter pays the duty. ","  D. The importer determines the tariff classification and pays the duty. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The exporter determines the tariff classification using the harmonized code when packaging the goods for export. The importer (usually through the customs house broker) pays the duty when goods come through customs.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following warehouse operations is most appropriate for a manufacturer that receives components from many suppliers and wants to achieve economies of scale when transporting those components to one plant?","choices":["A. Cross-dock ","  B. Consolidation ","  C. Break-bulk ","  D. Mixing "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"To achieve economies of scale in transportation, consolidation combines shipments from many incoming sources when loading outbound vehicles headed for a single location.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following warehouse operations would take place at a manufacturer's centralized warehouse to facilitate delivery of one product to many retailers?","choices":["A. Consolidation ","  B. Mixing ","  C. Spot stocking ","  D. Break-bulk"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Break-bulk operations break an incoming shipment from one source into smaller lots for reshipping to specific customers.  "},{"question":"Which of the following provides a point of reference for formulating the sales and operations plan?","choices":["A. Production forecast ","  B. Financial plan ","  C. Marketing plan ","  D. Business plan"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The sales and operations plan takes the business plan as its point of reference for developing a plan that balances supply and demand by merging input from sales and marketing on the one hand and operations on the other.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following functional areas is responsible for demand forecasting?","choices":["A. Executive team ","  B. IT ","  C. Purchasing ","  D. Sales and marketing "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The sales and marketing area is responsible and accountable for forecasting. Someone has to be responsible for the forecast for assessment purposes, but this does not mean that other areas cannot contribute to the forecast or that the forecast cannot be shared with other functional areas and supply chain partners. Information sharing is key to supply chain management.  "},{"question":"A business plan would typically include which of the following?","choices":["A. Definition of sales territories ","  B. Clearly defined marketing tactics ","  C. Monthly production figures for each product family ","  D. Long-term guidance for developing tactical production plans "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The business plan provides a long-range view of strategy and guidance for developing tactical plans for sales, marketing, and operations.  "},{"question":"A shipper whose exports are carried from the foreign port to the importer's dock by trucks that return empty to the port might hire which one of the following firms to find goods to carry on the backhaul route?","choices":["A. Non-vessel operating common carrier (NVOCC) ","  B. Export packager ","  C. Consolidator ","  D. Freight forwarder"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Consolidators specialize in filling trucks for backhaul journeys from import destinations to port when the importer provides no goods for carriage. The consolidator may have to consolidate small shipments from a number of exporters to fill the carriers. "},{"question":"Which one of the following types of warehousing is most appropriate for agricultural supplies that might be used only once during the year?","choices":["A. Assortment ","  B. Spot stocking ","  C. Stockpiling ","  D. Postponement"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Spot stocking is used for limited product lines and highly seasonal products that can be centrally stored during most of the year and spot-stocked in season at warehouses near the places where they will be purchased and used. Manufacturers use spot stocking for agricultural products used only during one limited operation, such as harvesting.  "},{"question":"Which of the following correctly identifies the cost structure of trucking?","choices":["A. Low fixed costs, high variable costs ","  B. High fixed costs, high variable costs ","  C. High fixed costs, low variable costs ","  D. Low fixed costs, low variable costs"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The public builds and maintains the infrastructure used by trucks, so they have low fixed costs. But they have relatively high variable costs for operation and maintenance.  "},{"question":"In a multiple-echelon distribution network where each warehouse orders independently based on local demand, where in the chain do you find the most variance in order quantity?","choices":["A. Variability tends to remain constant along the chain. ","  B. Variability tends to increase toward the raw materials end of the chain. ","  C. Variability tend to be greatest in the middle of the chain, diminishing toward either end. ","  D. Variability tends to increase toward the customer end of the chain."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"In many chains, variance in order quantity tends to increase as you move upstream away from the end customer. This is the bullwhip effect.  "},{"question":"Which of the following design strategies offers streamlined production and lower purchasing costs with a possible tradeoff against reduced design flexibility and lower quality?","choices":["A. Component commonality ","  B. Integral design ","  C. Mass customization ","  D. Universality "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Using common components for a variety of purposes provides economies of scale in purchasing and manufacture but can limit design flexibility and reduce quality.  "},{"question":"If you are making up a production schedule using the lot-for-lot sizing method, which of the following equations would you use to determine the planned order receipt (assuming you know the gross amount required)?","choices":["A. Gross requirement alone ","  B. Gross requirement minus projected amounts on hand ","  C. Gross requirement minus scheduled receipts ","  D. Gross requirement minus projected on hand minus scheduled receipts "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"In a lot-for-lot schedule, the planned order release is equal to net requirements (gross requirement reduced by any inventory on hand). There is unlikely to be inventory on hand except at the beginning of an order period.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following would a firm be most likely to choose to deliver goods in national markets if it is looking for tailored services and a relatively low negotiated rate?","choices":["A. Contract carrier ","  B. Exempt carrier ","  C. Common carrier ","  D. Private carrier "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Contract carriers can generally offer lower rates and tailored services to select clients.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following benefits has been realized under the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA)?","choices":["A. Elimination of barriers to transportation across the U.S.-Mexican border ","  B. Simplified documentation to qualify for lower tariffs on regional goods ","  C. Elimination of many regional tariffs ","  D. Easier access to competitively priced goods from outside the region "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"NAFTA eliminated many tariffs on imports originating from within the region and scheduled elimination of the rest. Other barriers, such as access to roads on either side of the U.S.-Mexican border, remain troublesome. Imports originating from countries within the region are granted favorable duties compared to goods from outside, but documenting country of origin can be troublesome.  "},{"question":"Referring to the table below, calculate a forecast for April using the three-month moving average method. Based on your calculation, which of the following statements correctly relates the forecast to the actual April demand of 22? ","choices":["A. Demand and forecast are the same. ","  B. Demand exceeds forecast by 1. ","  C. Demand exceeds forecast by 2. ","  D. Demand exceeds forecast by 3."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The average demand for the three months from January through March is 20 (21 + 17 + 22 = 60; 60 / 3 = 20), so the forecast for April is 20, which is two less than the actual demand.  "},{"question":"Which of the following offers the greatest security against loss of cargo when transporting petroleum?","choices":["A. Water ","  B. Rail ","  C. Road ","  D. Pipelines  "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Pipelines are considered a very secure way to convey liquid cargo. Except for earthquakes or terrorist attacks, pipelines will carry appropriate freight with almost no risk of loss or damage.  "},{"question":"Place the following modes of transportation in order of rate per ton-mile for carrying cargo, with I being the lowest rates and IV being the highest.","choices":["I. ","\tRail ","\tII. ","\tAir "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Water transport offers the lowest rates per ton, much lower even than rail, which is second. Trucking is considerably more expensive than rail but substantially less expensive than air.  "},{"question":"Which of the following would be subject to alteration as the result of decisions made in an executive S\u0026OP meeting?","choices":["A. Weekly production schedules ","  B. Business plan ","  C. Product features ","  D. Product pricing "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The monthly S\u0026OP meeting deals with aggregate-level information about product families and output. The S\u0026OP executive committee can make changes in either the operations plan or the business plan if they get out of synch with one another.  "},{"question":"Using a pull system in the distribution network offers which one of the following benefits to the supply chain as a whole?","choices":["A. Elimination of safety stock ","  B. Enhanced communication up the chain ","  C. Sensitivity to demands of the final customer ","  D. Enhanced visibility of future demand all along the chain"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The main benefit of the pull system of distribution is sensitivity to local customer demand, since orders begin near the customer and \"pull\" products from upstream. This approach does not facilitate communication, eliminate safety stock, or improve visibility down the chain because there is no central coordination and upstream partners have to depend upon forecasting to plan for future orders rather than upon (for example) a predetermined production schedule.  "},{"question":"Which of the following transportation stakeholders is most likely to be in agreement with the government about the need for market regulation?","choices":["A. Shippers ","  B. Carriers ","  C. Recipients ","  D. The public "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"All market participants can benefit from well-crafted regulations regarding such matters as fairness and safety, but the public at large is most likely to be in synch with the government on the broad spectrum of regulations, from pricing through access to safety and environmental stewardship. (This assumes a government that is responsive to public demands.)  "},{"question":"Considering the types of cargo typically carried over long distances by inland water carrier and the rates per ton-mile, which of the following modes of transportation is the barge's closest competitor?","choices":["A. Piggyback ","  B. Rail ","  C. Trucking ","  D. Pipeline"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Railroad and barges both specialize in carrying very heavy, dense, low-value cargo over long distances. A rail line laid along a waterway would make a potent rival for the water carrier.  "},{"question":"Referring to the demand table below, calculate a three-month weighted moving average forecast for April using a 3-2-1 weighting for March, February, and January, respectively. Which of the following identifies the correct forecast for April using this method? ","choices":["A. 20.17 ","  B. 20.33 ","  C. 20.67 ","  D. 40.33"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The three-month weighted moving average forecast for April is 20.17 (3 x 22 = 66; 2 x 17 = 34; 1 x 21 = 21; 66 + 34 + 21 = 121; 121 / 6 = 20.17). Did you remember to divide by the sum of the weights (6) instead of by 3?  "},{"question":"For make-to-stock production of an integral design, the master production schedule includes production dates for which of the following?","choices":["A. End items ","  B. Product families ","  C. Orders ","  D. Components"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The master production schedule includes dates of production for make-to-stock end items. (This can be either finished products or, in a modular approach, components.)  "},{"question":"Inventory held to cover transit time is called which of the following?","choices":["A. Work-in-process inventory ","  B. Fluctuation inventory ","  C. Pipeline inventory ","  D. Anticipatory inventory"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Pipeline inventory is stock kept on hand to fill orders while the next lot is in transit. It is also known as transportation inventory.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following processes results in production numbers driven by dependent demand?","choices":["A. Master production scheduling process ","  B. Sales and operations planning process ","  C. Material requirements planning process ","  D. Market planning process"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The MRP schedules delivery of dependent demand items (which are in turn based upon independent demand forecasts). The other processes work with independent demand or product families.  "},{"question":"Which of the following design strategies is the polar opposite of integral design?","choices":["A. Universality ","  B. Modular design ","  C. Mass customization ","  D. Design for postponement"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Modular design creates mix-and-match components that can be combined into different products, whereas integral design creates one product from a unique set of components.  "},{"question":"Expenses involved in the reverse logistics chain may be offset by which of the following?","choices":["A. Rebates from landfills ","  B. More efficient use of warehouses set up for forward logistics ","  C. Freight discounts on shipments of returned items ","  D. Sale of service contracts "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Revenue from the sale of service contracts can offset some of the expenses involved in the reverse logistics chain, including higher transportation fees for small, sporadic shipments; the addition of transportation lanes to reach specialized warehouses; and, of course, the costs to the company of making warranty repairs.  "},{"question":"A logistics manager concerned to avoid breakage of cargo would be least inclined to choose which of the following modes of transportation (ignoring tradeoffs)?","choices":["A. Water transport ","  B. Truck transport ","  C. Rail transport ","  D. Air transport "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Rail provides a rough ride for cargo, resulting in more breakage than occurs in cargo transported by truck, water, or air.  "},{"question":"Which of the following identifies a risk of ordering more inventory than required to fill forecast orders?","choices":["A. Increased obsolescence ","  B. Decoupling from supplier ","  C. Higher per-car costs for transporting the inventory ","  D. Higher per-item costs for purchasing the inventory"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The risk of having inventory items become obsolete increases when amounts ordered exceed the forecast significantly. Economies of scale in transport and purchase are potential benefits of larger orders, as is decoupling from the supplier.  "}]